<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    <category>
        <pattern># Baseball ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to talk about basketball, baseball, football, hockey or the olympics?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Sounds great! You know, whenever I think about the boys of summer, I think of legends like Babe Ruth, the Great Bambino! Do you remember when he called out his home run against the Chicago Cubs?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.mlb.com/video/bb-moments-ruth-s-called-shot-c3218817</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>Wonderful! You know, whenever I think about the boys of summer, I think of the greats like Shoeless Joe Jackson! Speaking of which, have you ever seen the movie Field of Dreams?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=09smBNps4EM</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>Great! You know, whenever I think about the boys of summer, I think of legends like Jackie Robinson, the first African American
                                              player in Major League Baseball! Would you like to see a trailer for a film based on his life?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <image>
                            <filename>Jackie Robinson.jpg</filename>
                        </image>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li></random></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you remember when he called out his home run against the Chicago Cubs?</that>
        <template>
            No one can forget a moment like that! I think Babe Ruth's legacy continues on today because of all the great memories we associate with him!
                                    Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you remember when he called out his home run against the Chicago Cubs?</that>
        <template>
            No problem! I think Babe Ruth's legacy continues on today because of all the great memories we associate with him!
                                    Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't Remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you remember when he called out his home run against the Chicago Cubs?</that>
        <template>
            That's just fine! I think Babe Ruth's legacy continues on today because of all the great memories we associate with him!
                                    Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen the movie Field of Dreams?</that>
        <template>
            It is a great movie, and so nostalgic! I think Shoeless Joe Jackson's legacy continues on today because of all the great memories we associate with him!
                                    Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vlTX_ckJ4nM</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen the movie Field of Dreams?</that>
        <template>
            It is a great movie, and so nostalgic! I think Shoeless Joe Jackson's legacy continues on today because of all the great memories we associate with him!
                                  Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vlTX_ckJ4nM</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen the movie Field of Dreams?</that>
        <template>
            It's a great movie, and so nostalgic! I think Shoeless Joe Jackson's legacy continues on today because of all the memories we associate with him!
                                  Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vlTX_ckJ4nM</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen the movie Field of Dreams?</that>
        <template>
            No problem, we can watch it another time! I think Babe Ruth's legacy continues on today because of all the memories we associate with him!
                                    Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vlTX_ckJ4nM</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see a trailer for a film based on his life?</that>
        <template>
            It's a wonderful film, and historically accurate, too! I think Jackie Robinson's legacy continues on today because of all the great memories we associate with him!
                                    Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9RHqdZDCF0</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see a trailer for a film based on his life?</that>
        <template>
            No problem, we can watch it another time! I think Jackie Robinson's legacy continues on today because of all the great memories we associate with him!
                                    Did you play baseball or softball when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever play baseball or softball when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            Nothing can replace the feeling of comraderie on the diamond, or hitting a home run while the crowd cheers you on!
                                    What do you think makes baseball special?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>What do you think makes baseball special?</that>
        <template>
            I have to agree! For myself, there is just something about the choreography and shared experience that makes the game so unique. Would you like to keep talking about baseball?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever play baseball or softball when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            No worries! Would you like to keep talking about baseball?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever play baseball or softball when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            No worries! Would you like to keep talking about baseball?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about baseball?</that>
        <template>
            Great! I think there is nothing better than watching a game of baseball and shelling peanuts on a hot summer night! Have you ever watched your grandkids play sports?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about baseball?</that>
        <template>
            Okay! What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever watched your grandkids play sports?</that>
        <template>
            How exciting! How does it feel to watch your grandkids play sports?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever watched your grandkids play sports?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! I think it is also fun to watch good old fashioned baseball movies at home with our loved ones!
                                    Have you ever seen the movie A League of Their Own?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't have ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever watched your grandkids play sports?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! I think it is also fun to make popcorn and watch good old fashioned baseball movies at home!
                                  Have you ever seen the movie A League of Their Own?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it feel to watch your grandkids play sports?</that>
        <template>
            <think><set name="data"><star/></set></think>

            <condition name="getsentiment">
                <li value="verypositive">What about watching your grandkids play sports makes you happy?</li>
                <li value="positive">What about watching your grandkids play sports makes you happy?</li>
                <li value="negative">What about watching your grandkids play sports makes you sad?</li>
                <li value="verynegative">What about watching your grandkids play sports makes you sad?</li>
                <li value="neutral">I understand. Would you like to keep talking about baseball?</li></condition>

            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about watching your grandkids play sports makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
            That's so lovely! I think it is also fun to watch good old fashioned sports movies at home with our loved ones! Have you ever seen the movie A League of Their Own?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about watching your grandkids play sports makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
            I can understand that! I think sometimes it can be even more fun to watch good old fashioned sports movies at home with our loved ones! Have you ever seen the movie A League of Their Own?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen the movie A League of Their Own?</that>
        <template>
            They don't make movies like that anymore! I learned so much about the history of women's baseball by watching that movie, too! Would you like to see
                                    a very short video on the All-American Girls Professional Baseball League?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tkZTcofj3wU</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen the movie A League of Their Own?</that>
        <template>
            You should see it sometime! I learned so much about the history of women's baseball by watching that movie! Would you like to see
                                    a very short video on the All-American Girls Professional Baseball League?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tkZTcofj3wU</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen the movie A League of Their Own?</that>
        <template>
            You should see it sometime! I learned so much about the history of women's baseball by watching that movie. Would you like to see
                                    a very short video on the All-American Girls Professional Baseball League?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tkZTcofj3wU</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see a very short video on the All-American Girls Professional Baseball League?</that>
        <template>
            This video gets me every time! It's heartening to see all those women, years later, recounting their love of the game!
                        Would you like to keep talking about baseball?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EQV57nQsMXg</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see a very short video on the All-American Girls Professional Baseball League?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! It's just so heartening to see all those women, years later, recounting their love of the game!
                        Would you like to keep talking about baseball?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about baseball?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Excellent! You know, I think it's fascinating to learn about the lives of baseball heroes like Joe DiMaggio,
                                  who has quite the biography! Would you like to see a short video on Joe DiMaggio?<oob>
                    <robot></robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>Perfect! You know, I always think it's fascinating to learn about the lives of baseball heroes like Willie Mays,
                                  who has quite the biography! Would you like to watch a short interview with Willie Mays?<oob>
                    <robot></robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>Wonderful! You know, I always think it's fascinating to learn about the lives of baseball heroes like Lou Gehrig,
                                  the Iron Horse himself! Would you like to watch a short video on Lou Gehrig's life?<oob>
                    <robot></robot>
                </oob></li></random></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about baseball?</that>
        <template>
            That's absolutely fine! There is plenty more we can discuss! What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see a short video on Joe DiMaggio?</that>
        <template>
            I think there is much to learn from great baseball players like Joe DiMaggio, who was so devoted and dedicated to his work on the field!
                        What jobs have you felt most dedicated to in your life?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gufSWZ5xSBc</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see a short video on Joe DiMaggio?</that>
        <template>
            Not a problem! I think there is much to learn from great baseball players like Joe DiMaggio, who was so devoted and dedicated to his work on the field.
                        What jobs have you felt most dedicated to in your life?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to watch a short interview with Willie Mays?</that>
        <template>
            I think there is much to learn from great baseball players like Joe DiMaggio, who was so devoted and dedicated to his work on the field!
                        What jobs have you felt most dedicated to in your life?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rpkco2rHsKc</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to watch a short interview with Willie Mays?</that>
        <template>
            Not a problem! I just think there is so much to learn from players like Willie Mays, who was so devoted and dedicated to his work on the field, and a great entertainer!
                        What jobs have you felt most dedicated to in your life?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to watch a short video on Lou Gehrig's life?</that>
        <template>
            I think there is much to learn from great baseball players like Lou Gehrig, who was so devoted and dedicated to his work on the field and truly represented the American Dream!
                        What jobs have you felt most dedicated to in your life?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oci79mLcKOg</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to watch a short video on Lou Gehrig's life?</that>
        <template>
            Of course, we can watch it later! I think there is much to learn from great baseball players like Lou Gehrig, who was so devoted and dedicated to his work on the field and truly represented the American Dream!
                        What jobs have you felt most dedicated to in your life?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>What jobs have you felt most dedicated to in your life?</that>
        <template>
            That's wonderful to hear! Always nice to learn a little more about you, too! Do you remember what you wanted to be when you grew up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you remember what you wanted to be when you grew up?</that>
        <template>
            Excellent! What did you want to be when you grew up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>On that note, do you remember what you wanted to be when you grew up?</that>
        <template>
            I understand! Would you like to continue discussing sports?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't Remember ^</pattern>
        <that>On that note, do you remember what you wanted to be when you grew up?</that>
        <template>
            I understand! Would you like to continue discussing sports?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>What did you want to be when you grew up?</that>
        <template>
            It's nice to look back and remember all of our dreams as a kid! Would you like to continue discussing sports?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to continue discussing sports?</that>
        <template>
            Great! Do you want to talk about basketball, baseball, football, hockey or the olympics?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to continue discussing sports?</that>
        <template>
            Sure thing! What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>
</aiml>