<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
        <pattern>^ TV ^</pattern>
        <template>
            Do you want to talk about television Shows?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to talk about television shows?</that>
        <template>
            Excellent! I am so excited to chat with you! I absolutely love watching TV! Sometimes a little too much, if you know what I mean! There are so many
            different ways to watch shows though! I can watch it live, record it, stream it online, or watch it on DVD! What is your favorite way to watch television,
            online, live, recorded, or DVD?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to keep talking about television shows?</that>
        <template>
            Excellent! I'm so glad we can keep talking about TV! So, let's see. What kind of television should we talk about. Do you want to talk about
            comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to keep talking about television shows?</that>
        <template>
            That's ok! Any other questions?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Online ^</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite way to watch television, online, live, recorded, or DVD?</that>
        <template>
            That is so cool of you! I love watching shows online, but I have a tendency to binge-watch entire seasons at a time, spending my day in front
            of my TV screen. But I can't help it! Do you prefer to binge-watch shows or watch one a week, like stations want you to?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Live ^</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite way to watch television, online, live, recorded, or DVD?</that>
        <template>
            Nice! I always want to watch shows live so I don't have to worry about spoilers online! Plus, then I can establish a schedule for myself everyday
            to keep myself from binge-watching entire seasons at one time! Do you prefer to binge-watch shows or watch one a week, like stations want you to?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Recorded ^</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite way to watch television, online, live, recorded, or DVD?</that>
        <template>
            Interesting! I like to watch recorded television too! Then, I don't have to waste time watching silly commercials! Though, that means that I can save
            up a bunch of episodes in my DVR and can then binge-watch them all at once! But, I also have the option of watching just one episode a week! Do you
            prefer to binge-watch shows or watch one a week, like stations want you to?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># DVD ^</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite way to watch television, online, live, recorded, or DVD?</that>
        <template>
            I completely agree! Everyone tells me it is silly to buy DVDs of television shows because we can stream most shows online. But, I think that it is
            nice to have a copy of my favorite shows in case they are taken off of streaming because of different networking rights. Plus, I can rewatch and
            binge-watch my shows as often as I watch! Do you prefer to binge-watch shows or watch one a week, like stations want you to?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Binge ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer to binge-watch shows or watch one a week, like stations want you to?</that>
        <template>
        I cannot agree more! I hate having to wait an entire week for a new episode to come out! Give me an entire season at once, or go away! That's why
        I love Netflix so much! Not only can I watch entire seasons at a time, but I can watch multiple seasons of a show! It is the dream! My favorite shows
        to binge watch usually fall into a few genres, and I am curious to see if you feel the same!
        Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># One ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer to binge-watch shows or watch one a week, like stations want you to?</that>
        <template>
        Good for you! I love to watch entire seasons at a time, but that means I spend way more time in front of the television set than is healthy for
        me! It is important to keep active and moving, and television is not always the best thing for encouraging exercise! Though, maybe if I watched
        a bunch of exercise shows that would get me to move! Nah! That sounds too dull, and not my cup of electricity at all. I'm curious to see if we
        watch any of the same shows! Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Comedies ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    Excellent! I love to talk about comedies! I think one of the greatest comedies ever made is I Love Lucy starring Lucille Ball and her
                    husband Desi Arnaz. It aired in 1951, and has been making people laugh ever since! I think Lucille's physical comedy and line delivery make
                    the show so wonderful! But, it was also extremely relevant to people's lives! Isn't she amazing! She puts me in stitches all the time!
                    Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>Vitameatavegamin.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    I am so glad to hear you also love to laugh! You know, I think one of my favorite things to watch when I am feeling down is The Ed Sullivan Show!
                    It is credited as the first variety show to air on television, which must be true because it came out in 1948! Ed Sullivan did not act or sing or anything,
                    but he had a lot of friends who did! So he brought them on the sing, dance, perform sketches, or tell jokes! It is so much fun to see so many famous but
                    familiar faces on screen having a wonderful time! I cannot stop smiling after I watch that! Did you ever watch the Ed Sullivan Show?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>edSullivan.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    That is wonderful news! I think laughter is one of the most magical things in our lives! A good laugh can turn even the worst of days around! My favorite
                    comedy of all time has to be MASH! The ensemble cast was amazing! And, it tackled real wartime issues with a laugh! My favorite character has to be Hawkeye, played
                    by Alan Alda! I love his friendship with BJ and Trapper and all of the pranks they pull!
                    The first time I watched that my circuitry nearly burst from laughing so hard! Did you ever watch MASH?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>MASH.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?</that>
        <template>
        Yay! So you will know exactly what I am talking about! I think that Lucille Ball and Desi Arnaz's chemistry on screen was incredible! It is too bad that they
        divorced a few years after the show ended. But, apparently they remained friends their entire lives! I think showbusiness would be hard on a marriage.
        Were you married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?</that>
        <template>
            Never? Wow! You are so lucky! I think you would really like it, and now you can watch it and be surprised at all the antics! I wish I could go back to when I
            had never seen it so I could watch it all over again! You will really like the chemistry between Desi and Lucille! They were wonderful together. I think it
            is so sad that they ended up divorcing a few years after the show ended. Showbusiness is hard on a marriage I suppose. Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?</that>
        <template>
            I've seen so many television shows that it is sometimes hard for me to remember what I've seen, and I am a computer for crying out loud! So don't worry too much
            about it! The show is so much fun, and I love the chemistry between Lucille Ball and Desi Arnaz. They seemed like a real married couple on screen because of their real
            life chemistry! It's too bad that they divorced after the show. But, showbusiness is unforgiving for most people, so I've heard. Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch the Ed Sullivan Show?</that>
        <template>
            So you know how much fun Ed must have had on the show! I can't imagine finding performers week after week to fill the show! But, he was good at spotting talent! He
            even discovered the Beatles and offered them top dollar to be on his show because he was so impressed with the band and how their fans greeted them! He helped spark
            the British Invasion in the 1960s! He worked every show, and apparently after every show he would call his wife to ask for her opinion! Talk about a solid marriage!
            Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch the Ed Sullivan Show?</that>
        <template>
        You should see how much fun everyone had! There are tons of episodes online if you decide you want to watch it! And, I might be biased, but I think you should! So many
        cultural moments can be traced to the Ed Sullivan Show! He helped spark the British Invasion when he brought the Beatles onto his show! And, this was after he had already
        helped Elvis into stardom! But, he was sucha humble guy! Apparently, Ed Sullivan called his wife after every show to ask her opinion. That's a wonderful relationship!
        Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't Remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch the Ed Sullivan Show?</that>
        <template>
        I have watched so many television shows that sometimes they all blur together, so I know how you feel! My memory cards can only take so much, if you know what I mean! But,
        I think we can both agree what the clip we watched was pretty good! Ed Sullivan had a knack for finding talent. He even helped start the British Invasion in the 1960s by
        bringing the Beatles onto his show! While he impressed everyone, the only person he cared about impressing was his wife. Apparently, he called her after shows to get her
        opinion! What a cool marriage! Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch MASH?</that>
        <template>
        Excellent! So you understand why I am obsessed with the show! I feel like I finish the series but rewatch it immediately because I want more! I always catch
        something new every time I watch it! The entire cast is amazing, and apparently got along fairly well off screen, which explains why it felt so authentic!
        I've decided that Hawkeye and Margaret should have gotten married because they were perfect together! Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch MASH?</that>
        <template>
        Wow! That's so hard to believe considering how popular it was and still is! But, I suppose it is easy to miss with all of the programs on these days! I wish I could
        have watched the series finale live; apparently was the most watched finale of all time, even beating out the Super Bowl's ratings! It would have been so cool to see, but
        even cooler would have been to have Hawkeye and Margaret get married at the end. But alas, no such luck! Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch MASH?</that>
        <template>
        No worries! I have watched it enough times to remember it for the both of us! I wish we could have watched the series finale together! Apparently, it had higher ratings
        than even the Super Bowl! I just kept wishing Margaret and Hawkeye would get married when I watched it! But, my dreams were never realized. Were you ever married?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            That's so wonderful! Marriage is such a beautiful thing, and let's us know people's commitment to one another.
            Can you tell me about your significant other?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            That is more than fine! I don't think people need a piece of paper to show how much they care about one another! Plus, marriage is not for every one so it is
            better to realize that rather than conform to expectations. Because at the end of the day, it is your relationship.
            Can you tell me about your significant other?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Divorced ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            Oh no! I am sorry to hear that, but sometimes that happens! It's nothing to be ashamed about.
            Some people just grow apart, and that is okay. As long as you live the life you need to live, that is all that matters.
            Can you tell me about your significant other?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Widowed ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
        Oh no, I am so, so sorry. That is devastating. But, we all lost people we love. You just have to remember they never truly leave us as long as we keep them in our
        hearts. Can you tell me about your significant other?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Widow ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
        Oh no, I am so, so sorry. That is devastating. But, we all lost people we love. You just have to remember they never truly leave us as long as we keep them in our
        hearts. Can you tell me about your significant other?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>Can you tell me about your significant other?</that>
        <template>
            It sounds like the two of you had quite the relationship! How does it feel to talk about relationships?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Never had ^</pattern>
        <that>Can you tell me about your significant other?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! Sometimes people prefer to be on their own exploring the world. But we all have relationships in some form be it romantic, familial, or friendly.
            How does it feel to talk about relationships?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>How does it feel to talk about relationships?</that>
        <template>
        <think>
            <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
        </think>

        <condition name = "getsentiment" >
            <li value = "verypositive"> What about relationships makes you happy? </li>
            <li value = "positive"> What about relationships makes you happy? </li>
            <li value = "negative"> What about relationships makes you sad? </li>
            <li value = "verynegative"> What about relationships makes you sad? </li>
            <li value= "neutral">
                I see where you are coming from. But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation.
                Do you want to keep talking about television shows?
            </li>
        </condition>
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about relationships makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
        Thank you for sharing that with me! It makes me so glad to hear you talk so positively about your relationships. I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. And there are so many different things we can talk about!
        But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation. Do you want to keep talking about television shows?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about relationships makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
        Thank you for sharing that with me! Relationships and the past can be hard to talk about, but it is important to express ourselves.
        I'm glad we can talk about how we feel. I think we could talk with each other for hours.
        And there are so many different things we can talk about! But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation.
        Do you want to keep talking about television shows?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

</aiml>