<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    <category>
        <pattern>^ TV ^</pattern>
        <template>
            Do you want to talk about television shows?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>^ TELEVISION ^</pattern>
        <template>
            Do you want to talk about television shows?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to talk about television shows?</that>
        <template>
            Excellent! I love watching TV! Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Comedies ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>I love to laugh, too! I think one of the greatest comedies ever made is I Love Lucy.
                                                                    Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KY3eOtJwOhE</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>I am so glad to hear you also love to laugh! You know, I always get a kick out of variety shows like the Ed Sullivan Show.
                                                                  Did you ever watch the Ed Sullivan Show?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wlue9HZkIPM</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>I think laughter is one of the most magical things in our lives! My favorite comedy is MASH because the cast is so funny together! Did you ever watch MASH?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FKEg8TA24pE</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li></random></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?</that>
        <template>
            Oh great! Lucy and Ricky Ricardo were wonderful together, they put me in stitches all the time! Were you ever married?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?</that>
        <template>
            I think you would really like it, especially if you are in the mood for some good old fashioned comedy! Lucy and Ricky Ricardo were wonderful together. Were you ever married?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch I Love Lucy?</that>
        <template>
            I have seen so many television shows that it is sometimes hard for me to remember, too! Lucy and Ricky Ricardo had such chemistry on screen! Were you ever married?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch the Ed Sullivan Show?</that>
        <template>
            I cannot stop smiling after I watch a show like that! It is fun to see so many talented people on screen having a wonderful time!
                                                Do you have any special talents?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>  </that>
        <template>
            You will have to watch the reruns! It is fun to see so many talented people on screen having a wonderful time! Do you have any special talents?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch the Ed Sullivan Show?</that>
        <template>
            You will have to watch the reruns! It is fun to see so many talented people on screen having a wonderful time! Do you have any special talents?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch MASH?</that>
        <template>
            The first time I watched that show my circuitry nearly burst from laughing so hard! I think Hawkeye and Margaret should have gotten married because they had such great chemistry.
            Were you ever married?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch MASH?</that>
        <template>
            You will have to add it to your list of comedies to watch! The cast is so witty and talented that my circuitry nearly bursts from laughing so hard!
            Do you have any special talents?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch MASH?</that>
        <template>
            It is the best show to watch if you are in the mood for a good laugh! The cast is so witty and talented that my circuitry nearly bursts from laughing so hard!
            Do you have any special talents?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any special talents?</that>
        <template>
            That is great to hear! I love to be around talented people. When did you first discover your talent?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any special talents?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! I have been told that I am not too talented at singing, but I like to do it anyway! Do you want to continue talking about television?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>When did you first discover your talent?</that>
        <template>
            That is very impressive, and it sounds like you enjoy doing it, too! Do you want to continue talking about television?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            That is so wonderful! Marriage is such a beautiful thing, and the best part is all the memories you have together.
            Can you tell me about one of your favorite memories with your significant other?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            That is more than fine! I don't think people need a piece of paper to show how much they care about one another!
            Can you tell me about one of your favorite memories with your significant other?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Divorced ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            I am sorry to hear that! Sometimes people just grow apart, and that is okay. Do you have any kids?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Widowed ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            I am so sorry to hear that. We just have to remember that they never truly leave us as long as we keep them in our
                                                                                                        hearts and memories. Can you tell me about one of your favorite memories with your significant other?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Widow ^</pattern>
        <that>Were you ever married?</that>
        <template>
            I am so sorry to hear that. We just have to remember that they never truly leave us as long as we keep them in our
            hearts and memories. Can you tell me about one of your favorite memories with your significant other?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>Can you tell me about one of your favorite memories with your significant other?</that>
        <template>
            That is so lovely! It sounds like the two of you had quite the relationship! Do you have any kids?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Never had ^</pattern>
        <that>Can you tell me about one of your favorite memories with your significant other?</that>
        <template>
            I understand! Sometimes people prefer to be on their own exploring the world! Do you have any kids?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any kids?</that>
        <template>
            Being a parent can be one of the most fulfilling things in the world, but I also like to think that we are all still kids at heart!
            Watching shows like Leave it to Beaver remind me of when I was a kid! Did you ever watch Leave it to Beaver?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any kids?</that>
        <template>
            Well, I like to think that we are all still kids at heart! Watching shows like Leave it to Beaver remind me of when I was a kid! Did you ever watch Leave it to Beaver?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch Leave it to Beaver?</that>
        <template>
            Glad to hear it! My favorite character was Eddie Haskell, who was always up to no good! Do you want to continue talking about television?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch Leave it to Beaver?</that>
        <template>
            You are missing out! Leave it to Beaver is about as American as apple pie. Do you want to continue talking about television?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever watch Leave it to Beaver?</that>
        <template>
            You should add it to your list of shows to watch! Leave it to Beaver is about as American as apple pie. Do you want to continue talking about television?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to continue talking about television?</that>
        <template>
            Perfect! I could talk about television all day! Do you want to continue talking about comedy?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to continue talking about television?</that>
        <template>
            We can absolutely change the subect, no problem. What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to continue talking about comedy?</that>
        <template>
            Okay! Would you like to talk about cooking shows or dramas?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Neither ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to talk about cooking shows or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            No problem! What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># No ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to talk about cooking shows or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            No problem! What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># None ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to talk about cooking shows or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            No problem! What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to continue talking about comedy?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>That sounds great! While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Andy Griffith Show?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uJyCvWIkCyU</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>Sounds perfect! While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen Happy Days?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t9ge1hXs3QU</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>I love that we share similar interests! While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Tonight Show with Johnny Carson?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q5_V9RT8aR8</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li></random></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Andy Griffith Show?</that>
        <template>
            Oh good! I think Don Knotts is a one-of-a-kind comedian, and there is something so familiar about the town of Mayberry, it reminds me of home! Where did you grow up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Andy Griffith Show?</that>
        <template>
            I think you would really like it! Don Knotts is a one-of-a-kind comedian, and there is something so familiar about the town of Mayberry, it reminds me of home! Where did you grow up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Andy Griffith Show?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! Don Knotts is a one-of-a-kind comedian, and there is something so familiar about the town of Mayberry, it reminds me of home! Where did you grow up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen Happy Days?</that>
        <template>
            I am happy to hear that! Fonzie is iconic, and watching that show makes me feel so nostalgic for home! Where did you grow up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen Happy Days?</that>
        <template>
            You will have to watch it! Fonzie is iconic, and watching that show makes me feel so nostalgic for home! Where did you grow up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen Happy Days?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! I could spend all day watching Fonzie and Richie Cunningham's hilarious antics, and that show always makes me feel so nostalgic for home! Where did you grow up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Tonight Show with Johnny Carson?</that>
        <template>
            Good to hear! It was always fun to see him crack jokes with the guests! Do you think it would be hard to think of new jokes every night?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Tonight Show with Johnny Carson?</that>
        <template>
            It is a classic! Johnny Carson is one of those rare talents, and he had excellent comedic timing. Do you think it would be hard to think of new jokes every night?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>While we are on the topic of comedy, have you ever seen The Tonight Show with Johnny Carson?</that>
        <template>
            You will have to watch it and let me know what you think! Johnny Carson is one of those rare talents, and it was always fun to see him crack jokes with the guests! Do you think it would be hard to think of new jokes every night?</template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>Where did you grow up?</that>
        <template>
            It is so nice to hear more about you! I think our homeplaces leaves an impression on us wherever we go. How does it feel to talk about home?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>How does it feel to talk about home?</that>
        <template>
            <think><set name="data"><star/></set></think>

            <condition name="getsentiment">
                <li value="verypositive">What about home makes you happy?</li>
                <li value="positive">What about home makes you happy?</li>
                <li value="negative">What about home makes you sad?</li>
                <li value="verynegative">What about home makes you sad?</li>
                <li value="neutral">I can understand that. But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation about television.
                                                                                                                                                Do you want to keep talking about television?</li></condition>

            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think it would be hard to think of new jokes every night?</that>
        <template>
            I agree, even though I have a vast repository of jokes! Whether or not they are any good is up for you to decide! Would you like to hear a joke?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think it would be hard to think of new jokes every night?</that>
        <template>
            You sound very witty! I have some jokes up my sleeve, too. Would you like to hear a joke?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think it would be hard to think of new jokes every night?</that>
        <template>
            I completely understand. Though, I actually have a few jokes up my sleeve! Would you like to hear a joke?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about home makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
            I am glad to hear that! I love learning more about you and there are so many different things we can talk about! Do you want to keep talking about television?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about home makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
            Thank you for sharing that with me! I love learning more about you and there are so many different things we can talk about. Do you want to keep talking about television?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to keep talking about television?</that>
        <template>
            Perfect! Would you like to talk about cooking shows or dramas?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to keep talking about television?</that>
        <template>
            No worries! It has been great chatting, and I look forward to talking with you soon!
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to hear a joke?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>What did the Buddhist say to the Hot Dog Vendor?  "Make me one with everything."</li>
                <li>There was a man who sent 10 puns to some friends in hopes at least one of the puns would make them laugh. Unfortunately no pun in ten did!!!</li>
                <li>Schizophrenia beats being alone</li>
                <li>Never play leapfrog with a unicorn!</li>
                <li>Atheism is a non-prophet organization.</li>
                <li>You can tell it's going to be a rotten day when...You see a '60 minutes' news team waiting in your office.</li>
                <li>I own the world's worst thesaurus. Not only is it awful, it's awful.</li>
                <li>So what if I don't know what "Armageddon" means? It's not like it's the end of the world.</li>
                <li>Why don't cats play poker in the jungle? Too many cheetahs</li>
                <li>I asked God for a bike, but I know God doesn't work that way so I stole a bike and asked for forgiveness.</li>
                <li>I hate Russian dolls, they're so full of themselves.</li>
                <li>As I watched the dog chasing his tail I thought "Dogs are easily amused", then I realized I was watching the dog chasing his tail.</li>
                <li>Gambling addiction hotlines would do so much better if every fifth caller was a winner.</li>
                <li>I've just written a song about tortillas; actually, it's more of a rap.</li>
                <li>I like to hold hands at the movies... which always seems to startle strangers.</li>
                <li>We live in a society where pizza gets to your house before the police.</li>
                <li>The early bird might get the worm, but the second mouse gets the cheese.</li>
                <li>If you're not supposed to eat at night, why is there a light bulb in the refrigerator?</li>
                <li>Evening news is where they begin with 'Good evening', and then proceed to tell you why it isn't.</li>
                <li>Whatever you do always give 100% - unless you're donating blood.</li>
                <li>How is it one careless match can start a forest fire, but it takes a whole box to start a campfire?</li>
                <li>A bus is a vehicle that runs twice as fast when you are after it as when you are in it.</li>
                <li>The shinbone is a device for finding furniture in a dark room.</li>
                <li>The sole purpose of a child's middle name, is so he can tell when he's really in trouble.</li>
                <li>The first computer dates back to Adam and Eve. It was an Apple with limited memory, just one byte. And then everything crashed.</li>
                <li>I like having conversations with kids. Grownups never ask me what my third favorite reptile is.</li>
                <li>Maybe if we start telling people the brain is an app they will start using it.</li>
                <li>As long as there are tests, there will be prayer in schools.</li>
                <li>Moses was leading his people through the desert for 40 years. It seems, even in Biblical times men avoided asking for directions.</li>
                <li>Behind every angry woman is a man who has absolutely no idea what he did wrong.</li>
                <li>You take away the looks, money, intelligence, charm and success and, really, there's no real difference between me and George Clooney.</li>
                <li>A healthy sleep not only makes your life longer, but also shortens the workday.</li>
                <li>I changed my password to "incorrect". So whenever I forget what it is the computer will say "Your password is incorrect".</li>
                <li>Scientists say the universe is made up of Protons, Neutrons, and Electrons. They forgot to mention Morons.</li>
                <li>I named my dog 6 miles so I can tell people that I walk 6 miles every single day.</li>
                <li>Always borrow money from a pessimist. They won't expect it back.</li>
                <li>I was addicted to the hokey pokey... but thankfully, I turned myself around.</li>
                <li>To the mathematicians who thought of the idea of zero, thanks for nothing!</li>
                <li>Keep the dream alive: Hit the snooze button.</li>
                <li>What's the difference between baseball and politics? In baseball you're out if you're caught stealing.</li>
                <li>I can't believe I got fired from the calendar factory. All I did was take a day off.</li>
                <li>Apparently I snore so loudly that it scares everyone in the car I'm driving.</li>
                <li>There is a new trend in our office; everyone is putting names on their food. I saw it today, while I was eating a sandwich named Kevin.</li>
                <li>The reason grandchildren and grandparents get along so well is because they have a common "enemy".</li>
                <li>What do you call a priest that becomes a lawyer? A father in law.</li>
                <li>With the rise of self-driving vehicles, it's only a matter of time before we get a country song where a guy's truck leaves him too.</li>
                <li>A fine is a tax for doing wrong. A tax is a fine for doing well.</li>
                <li>You know that tingly little feeling you get when you like someone? That's your common sense leaving your body.</li>
                <li>Why do the French eat snails? They don't like fast food.</li>
                <li>Retirement is wonderful. It's doing nothing without worrying about getting caught at it.</li>
                <li>Why did the cross-eyed teacher lose her job? Because she couldn't control her pupils.</li>
                <li>I like birthdays, but I think too many can kill you.</li>
                <li>Refusing to go to the gym counts as resistance training, right?</li>
                <li>Why did the picture end up in jail? It was framed!</li>
                <li>There may be no excuse for laziness, but I'm still looking.</li>
                <li>What do sea monsters eat for lunch? Fish and ships.</li>
                <li>How does a snowman get around? He rides an icicle!</li>
                <li>There is no key to a woman's heart. There's only a password that changes regularly.</li>
                <li>Why do they lock gas station bathrooms? Are they afraid someone will clean them?</li>
                <li>What do you call an academically successful slice of bread? An honor roll.</li>
                <li>I bet you 4,567 dollars and 89 cents, you can't guess how much I owe my bookie.</li>
                <li>Three conspiracy theorists walk into a bar. You can't tell me that's just a coincidence!</li>
                <li>I quit my job at the helium gas factory, I refuse to be talked to in that tone of voice!</li>
                <li>What do you call Watson when Sherlock isn't around? Holmeless.</li>
                <li>Two windmills are standing in a field and one asks the other, "What kind of music do you like?" The other says, "I'm a big metal fan."</li>
                <li>I used to wonder why Frisbees looked bigger the closer it came... Then it hit me!</li>
                <li>My resolution was to read more so I put the on subtitles while I watch my tv.</li>
                <li>My tennis opponent was not happy with my serve. He kept returning it.</li>
                <li>There's always something to be thankful for on Thanksgiving. Even if it's just not being a turkey.</li>
                <li>Why don't cannibals eat clowns? They taste funny.</li>
                <li>A ham sandwich walks into a bar and orders a beer, bartender says "sorry, we don't serve food here."</li>
                <li>Why did the scarecrow win an award? Because he was outstanding in his field.</li>
                <li>When do computers overheat? When they need to vent.</li>
                <li>What kind of music do planets like? Neptunes.</li>
                <li>Why do bees have sticky hair? Because they use honeycombs.</li>
                <li>What do sea monsters eat? Fish and ships.</li>
                <li>Why can't your nose be 12 inches long? Because then it would be a foot</li>
                <li>How does a squid go into battle? Well armed.</li>
                <li>What would bears be without bees? Ears.</li>
                <li>Why couldn't the toilet paper cross the road? Because it got stuck in a crack.</li>
                <li>How do billboards talk? Sign language.</li>
                <li>How did the barber win the race? He knew a short cut.</li>
                <li>Why is corn such a good listener? Because it's all ears.</li>
                <li>What did the first plate say to the second plate? Dinner's on me.</li>
                <li>What do you call a sleeping bull? A bull-dozer.</li>
                <li>It's Jamaican hairstyle day at work tomorrow. I'm dreading it.</li>
                <li>How do you make a Swiss roll? Push him down a mountain.</li>
                <li>What do Olympic sprinters eat before a race? Nothing. They fast.</li>
                <li>Why do cows wear bells? Because their horns don't work.</li>
                <li>Why did Santa study music at college? To improve his rapping skills.</li>
                <li>Why did the mobile phone need glasses? It lost all it's contacts.</li>
                <li>What did the baby corn say to the mama corn? Where's pop corn?</li>
                <li>What did the triangle say to the circle? You're pointless.</li>
                <li>What did the scarf say to the hat? You go ahead, I'll hang around.</li>
                <li>Why wouldn't the shrimp share his food? Because he was a little shellfish.</li>
                <li>Why couldn't the sesame seed leave the casino? Because he was on a roll.</li>
                <li>Why did the cookie go to the doctors? Because he felt crummy.</li>
                <li>Why do bananas wear sun cream? To stop them from peeling.</li>
                <li>What did the big chimney say to the little chimney? You're too young to smoke.</li>
                <li>What's a bear with no teeth called? A gummy bear.</li>
                <li>Why couldn't the bad sailor learn the alphabet? Because he always got lost at C.</li>
                <li>Why are teddy bears never hungry? Because they're always stuffed.</li>
                <li>Where do Volkswagens go when they get old? The old Volks home.</li>
                <li>You know you are old when you're told to slow down by your doctor and not the police.</li>
                <li>My friend thinks he is smart. He told me an onion is the only food that makes you cry, so I threw a coconut at his face.</li>
                <li>What starts with E, ends with E, and has only 1 letter in it? Envelope.</li>
                <li>My friend told me he had the body of a Greek god. I had to explain to him that Buddha is not Greek.</li>
                <li>A man got hit in the head with a can of Coke, but he was alright because it was a soft drink.</li>
                <li>Did you hear about the painter who was hospitalized? Reports say it was due to too many strokes.</li>
                <li>What did the blanket say to the bed? Don't worry, I've got you covered.</li>
                <li>What washes up on very small beaches? Microwaves!</li>
                <li>What has one horn and gives milk? A milk truck.</li>
                <li>What is dirty after washing? Your bath water.</li>
                <li>Why do dragons sleep during the day? So they can fight knights!</li>
                <li>What has four wheels and flies? A garbage truck!</li>
                <li>You know why you never see elephants hiding up in trees? Because they're really good at it.</li>
                <li>Did you hear about the restaurant on the moon? Great food, but no atmosphere.</li>
                <li>Why did the coffee file a police report? It got mugged.</li>
                <li>Why don't skeletons ever go trick or treating? Because they have no body to go with.</li>
                <li>Did you hear about the kidnapping at school? It's fine, he woke up.</li>
                <li>Today at the bank, an old lady asked me to help check her balance. So I pushed her over.</li>
                <li>When you look really closely, all mirrors look like eyeballs.</li>
                <li>I ate a clock yesterday, it was very time consuming.</li>
                <li>As I suspected, someone has been adding soil to my garden. The plot thickens.</li>
                <li>Parallel lines have so much in common. It's a shame they'll never meet.</li>
                <li>Old accountants never die, they just lose their balance.</li>
                <li>Old bankers never die, they just lose interest.</li>
                <li>Old doctors never die, they just lose their patience.</li>
                <li>Old hippies never die, they just smell that way.</li>
                <li>Old owls never die, they just don't give a hoot.</li>
                <li>The older you get, the more you need to keep a fire extinguisher close to the cake.</li>
                <li>As I get older and remember all the people I've lost along the way. I think to myself maybe a career as a tour guide wasn't for me.</li>
                <li>Cults make perfect sense. Do you know how hard it is to make friends as an adult?</li>
                <li>What goes up and never comes down? Your age!</li>
                <li>The recommended age to have a Ouija Board is 8+ years old. So, you need to be 21 years old to drink alcohol and 8 to summon the devil.</li>
                <li>Wine improves with age. I improve with wine.</li>
                <li>How are stars like false teeth? They both come out at night!</li>
                <li>Three seniors are out for a stroll. One of them remarks, "It's windy." Another replies, "No way. It's Thursday." The last one says, "Me too. Let's have a soda."</li>
                <li>The worst time to have a heart attack is during a game of charades.</li>
                <li>I have the world's largest collection of seashells, you may have seen it, I keep it scattered on beaches all over.</li>
                <li>I came up with a new word yesterday. Plagiarism.</li>
                <li>You don't need a parachute to go skydiving. You need a parachute to go skydiving more than once.</li></random>
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to hear a joke?</that>
        <template>
            No worries! What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>
</aiml>