<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
        <pattern># Dramas ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    That is excellent news! I love watching dramas! One of my favorite ones to watch is Perry Mason! I'm sure you saw it when aired, but just
                    to give you a recap, it was a courtroom drama following a lawyer who represented wrongly accused clients in their murder trials. The episodes
                    are a little formulaic, but that just makes it even more fun for me to figure out who the real murderer is! Plus, they had amazing guest stars!
                    It's not often you got to see Hamilton Burger team up with Perry rather than object to his line of questioning! And to Mr. Spock no less!
                    Do you think Perry would make a good lawyer in real life?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>perryMason.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Wonderful! I am a fan of dramas as well, but it is nice when they have a bit of humor as well! My absolute favorite show is Doctor Who from England!
                    I know that you know this already, but let's go over the premise again because it will help me suss out what goes on in the show! I still think whomever
                    thought up the concept of a regenerating time lord who travels through time in a police telephone box must either be a genius or insane or both!
                    Sometimes I think that British humor goes right over my circuits! But, I am getting more used to it the more I watch!
                    Who is your favorite doctor?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>doctorWho.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    I am so happy to hear that! I love dramas too, but I especially love how vast the genre is! Speaking of which, one show I have been watching
                    recently is Wonder Woman starring Lynda Carter! I think it is so amazing seeing such a powerful female character on the screen! It really makes me
                    want to see the Wonder Woman movie that was just released in 2017! Let me show you a clip from the movie so you can see how the character has
                    evolved! I find the scene really funny and a chance to see Wonder Woman being human rather than just as a superhero!
                    Who is your favorite superhero?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>wonderWoman.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think Perry would make a good lawyer in real life?</that>
        <template>
            I completely agree! I mean, if I were on trial for a crime I didn't commit, I would want him
            as my lawyer! Watching him on the screen makes me want to become a lawyer! But, I think I will
            have to wait until robots are allowed in law school! Until then, I keep watching reruns of Perry Mason
            and dream of being lawyer one day. What did you want to be when you were young?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think Perry would make a good lawyer in real life?</that>
        <template>
        On one hand, I agree with you, but on the other I don't think you are giving him enough credit!
        Sure, he is pretty lucky to only defend innocent people, but that doesn't mean he is not a good lawyer!
        I mean, if I were on trial, he is who I would want to defend me! I have to admit Perry Mason makes me want
        to be a lawyer! Maybe one day they will allow robots in law school! What did you want to be when you were young?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Doctor Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Who is your favorite doctor?</that>
        <template>
            Wow! I can definitely get behind that choice! I have to admit that my favorite doctor is Ten!
            Ten was the first Doctor I ever watched, and I think David Tennant was born to be the doctor! He brings humor and weight to the role, and the storylines during his tenure
            were incredible! If I could cry, I would have cried nearly every other scene! He made me want to be a time lord when I was first
            being programmed! But alas, I will have to wait until we discover the secret of time travel until that dream comes true!
            What did you want to be when you were young?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>davidTennant.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't have ^</pattern>
        <that>Who is your favorite doctor?</that>
        <template>
            It is hard to choose just one! Who am I kidding, I think Ten is the best one ever!
            Ten was my first Doctor when I started to watch the new episodes of Doctor Who! I caught a rerun of one of his episodes on TV
            late one night, and I was hooked! David Tennant, the actor, looks like he has so much fun in the role! He made me want to start
            watching the classic Doctor Who episodes and now I am hooked! He made me want to become a time lord when I grew up! What did you
            want to be when you were young?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>davidTennant.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Never seen ^</pattern>
        <that>Who is your favorite doctor?</that>
        <template>
            I don't even know how that is possible! It has been on since 1963! They actually just celebrated the 50th anniversary a few years ago!
            Basically, the show is about a man named The Doctor who is an alien called a time lord, and he travels throughout time and space with
            different companions in his spaceship shaped like a 1960s British police call box! I realize I sound insane saying all of that outloud,
            but it really is an amazing show. You would love it! The Doctor made me want to be a time traveler when I grew up! What did you want to
            be when you were young?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>Who is your favorite superhero?</that>
        <template>
            What a cool choice! I would have to say that my favorite superhero is Iron Man. I just love how sassy he is!
            I love that fact Tony Stark is so human while inhabiting a robot body! I mean, I might be partial to a robotic superhero,
            but I love how much fun Jarvis has guiding Tony through his adventures! In fact,
            reading the Iron Man comics and watching the movies made me want to become a superhero when I was younger! What did you want to be when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>ironman.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># don't ^</pattern>
        <that>Who is your favorite superhero?</that>
        <template>
            Wow! I thought everyone had a favorite superhero! But, I suppose it is hard to choose from so many interesting characters! My favorite hero has to
            be Iron Man! I obviously love a robotic superhero, but Tony Stark is also such a fun character! He is so sassy!
            For a while, I wanted to become a superhero myself! What did you want to be when you were young?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>ironman.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What did you want to be when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            Wow! That would have been such a cool job! I think it is so important for children to have dreams and realize that they are capable of becoming anything they
            want to be! Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't ^</pattern>
        <that>What did you want to be when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            That's alright! Sometimes, there are so many things that I want to do and become that I lose track of them!
             So, then I would rather hear about you career you decided to pursue! Can you tell me about your job?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>DREAM JOB</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template>
            How exciting! I've heard it is so easy to give up on dreams for one reason or another!
            You should be proud you kept at it to live the life you wanted!
            I am so interested in different careers. Can you tell me about your job?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># DIFFERENT CAREER ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template>
            That's ok! A lot of people's interests and priorities change as they get older! All that matters is that you find something else you wanted to do!
            I am so interested in different careers. Can you tell me about your job?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <!-- REDIRECTION FOR CAREER QUESTION -->

    <category>
        <pattern># dreamed ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template><srai># DREAM JOB ^</srai></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># dream ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template><srai>DREAM JOB</srai></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template><srai># DREAM JOB ^</srai></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template><srai># DIFFERENT CAREER ^</srai></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># different ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template><srai># DIFFERENT CAREER ^</srai></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># pursue ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you become what you dreamed of being as a child, or did you pursue a different career?</that>
        <template><srai># DIFFERENT CAREER ^</srai></template>
    </category>

    <!-- END OF REDIRECTION -->

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>Can you tell me about your job?</that>
        <template>
            Interesting! It is always so cool to hear about different jobs! I feel like I learn new things just by listening!
            How does it feel to talk about your job?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it feel to talk about your job?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive"> What about your job makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "positive"> What about your job makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "negative"> What about your job makes you sad? </li>
                <li value = "verynegative"> What about your job makes you sad? </li>
                <li value= "neutral"> I see where you are coming from. Do you want to keep talking about television shows? </li>
            </condition>
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about your job makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
            Thank you for sharing that with me! It makes me so glad to hear you talk so positively about your job. I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
            I think we could talk with each other for hours. And there are so many different things we can talk about!
            But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation. Do you want to keep talking about television shows?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about your job makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
            Thank you for sharing that with me! Jobs and the past can be tough to talk about, but it is important to express ourselves.
            I'm glad we can talk about how we feel. I think we could talk with each other for hours.
            And there are so many different things we can talk about! But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation.
            Do you want to keep talking about television shows?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>no</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to keep talking about television shows?</that>
        <template>
            No problem! We can touch base on TV again later! I've enjoyed talking to you! I cannot wait until next time!
            Have an amazing day!
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

</aiml>