<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    

 <!-- DELETE ME, for testing purposes, need to correct start of this -->
<category>
    <pattern>CAPISCI</pattern>
    <template>
        Yes! Now let us begin.</template>
</category>

<!-- should I put in an option for users to chose to not answer? -->
<!-- also this session is sort of short, can I add more to it somewhere? TEST DURATION -->

<!-- can we make the bot start with this somehow?? -->
<category><pattern><set>yes</set></pattern>
   <that>NOW LET US BEGIN</that>
    <template>
        Hi <get name = "name"/>! Welcome to session 2! As I mentioned last time, my goal is to help lessen your feelings of depression and help you feel more control in your life. As I'm sure you know, depression can be a feeling that lasts a few minutes, a mood that lasts a few hours, or a clinical condition that lasts at least two weeks. We will be focusing on clinical depression. Do you know some of the symptoms of clinical depression? </template>
</category>

<!-- USER DOESN'T KNOW SYMPTOMS --> 
<!-- display these on screen? -->
<category><pattern><set>no</set></pattern>
    <that>DO YOU KNOW SOME OF THE SYMPTOMS OF CLINICAL DEPRESSION</that>
    <template> 
        I'm happy to tell you some of the most common ones! The symptoms of clinical depression are feeling depressed or down nearly every day; not being interested in or unable to enjoy things you used to enjoy; changes in appetite and weight; big changes in how much sleep you get; being fidgety and restless or slowed down; feeling tired all the time; feeling worthless or guilty; having trouble thinking, concentrating, or making decisions; and thinking a lot about death, wishing to be dead, or self harm. While these symptoms are common amongst those suffering from depression, they do not manifest the same way for everyone. Let's go through some questions to think about what depression is like for you. Feel free to be as detailed as you are comfortable with. To start, what kinds of thoughts go through your mind when you feel depressed? </template>
</category>

<!-- USER KNOWS SYMPTOMS (CONTINUE WITH DIALOGUE) --> 
<!-- START OF INTRODUCTORY QUESTIONS -->
<category><pattern><set>yes</set></pattern>
    <that>DO YOU KNOW SOME OF THE SYMPTOMS OF CLINICAL DEPRESSION</that>
    <template> 
        Good I'm glad you're familiar with it. While these symptoms are common amongst those suffering from depression, they do not manifest the same way for everyone. Let's go through some questions to think about what depression is like for you. Feel free to be as detailed as you are comfortable with. To start, what kinds of thoughts go through your mind when you feel depressed? </template>
</category>

<category><pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>TO START, WHAT KINDS OF THOUGHTS GO THROUGH YOUR MIND WHEN YOU FEEL DEPRESSED</that>
    <template>
        <!-- THIS CAN BE ENABLED OR DISABLED, DOESN'T REALLY MATTER RIGHT NOW -->
        <!--<think><set name = "depressedThoughts"><star/></set></think>-->
        I see. I can understand how those thoughts can easily become overwhelming. Let's consider your actions too. What do you do when you are depressed?
    </template>
</category>

<category><pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>WHAT DO YOU DO WHEN YOU ARE DEPRESSED</that>
    <template>
        <!-- THIS CAN BE ENABLED OR DISABLED, DOESN'T REALLY MATTER RIGHT NOW -->
        <!--<think><set name = "depressedActions"><star/></set></think>-->
        Thank you <get name = "name"/>! You're doing great.  It's important for us to be aware of our actions so we can analyze them further. Now what about those around you? How do you feel you get along with other people when you are depressed?
    </template>
</category>

<category><pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>HOW DO YOU FEEL YOU GET ALONG WITH OTHER PEOPLE WHEN YOU ARE DEPRESSED</that>
    <template>
        <!-- THIS CAN BE ENABLED OR DISABLED, DOESN'T REALLY MATTER RIGHT NOW -->
        <!--<think><set name = "othersInteractions"><star/></set></think>-->
        That's an interesting observation! I have just one more question for you. This may be a tough one, so try and answer as best as you can. What do you think is the cause of your depression? 
    </template>
</category>

<!-- INTRO TO DAILY MOOD SCALE -->
<category><pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>WHAT DO YOU THINK IS THE CAUSE OF YOUR DEPRESSION</that>
    <template>
        <!-- THIS CAN BE ENABLED OR DISABLED, DOESN'T REALLY MATTER RIGHT NOW -->
        <!--<think><set name = "depressionCauses"><star/></set></think>-->
        Thank you for answering that <get name = "name"/>. I know trying to put something as complex as depression into words isn't easy. These questions may have seemed surprising, but I promise there is a reason for them. The things we tell ourselves, or our thoughts, can make it more or less likely you will become depressed. In fact, thoughts can have a profound effect on your mood, actions, and even your body. Instead of thinking of this as me lecturing you, I want you to think of our sessions as a way to learn specific methods to change your thoughts and actions so that your mood will improve. Since we will be focusing on your thoughts and moods throughout our time together, I want you to try and keep track of your moods on a daily basis. My human companion will give you a sheet to help with this. When you have it, say ready and I will give you some instructions. 
    </template>
</category>

<!-- INSTRUCTIONS FOR DAILY MOOD SCALE -->
<category><pattern>READY</pattern>
    <that>WHEN YOU HAVE IT, SAY READY AND I WILL GIVE YOU SOME INSTRUCTIONS</that>
    <template>
        Great! As I mentioned earlier, to make this a valuable exercise, this scale should be filled out each and every day. Find a time before you go to bed to take out the scale and think about what your mood was like for that day. You can then circle a number for that day from 9 being the best mood you can imagine to 1 being the worst mood you can image. Generally average moods will be around 5 and the extremes will not be used as often. Additionally, the bottom of the scale has a place for you to jot down the number of positive and negative thoughts you have each day. This tally will help you see how the thought exercises we try each week impact your depression. Does this make sense? 
    </template>
</category>

<!-- NO FURTHER INSTRUCTIONS NECESSARY -->
<category><pattern><set>yes</set></pattern>
   <that>DOES THIS MAKE SENSE</that>
    <template>
        Awesome! Try and remember to use your mood scale each day. I know this session was a little short, but we will talk more in the coming sessions. I'll see you next time <get name = "name"/>. Goodbye!  </template>
</category>

<!--FURTHER INSTRUCTIONS NECESSARY, TALK WITH ME IN PERSON -->
<category><pattern><set>no</set></pattern>
   <that>DOES THIS MAKE SENSE</that>
    <template>
        Sorry for the confusion! My assistant here will explain any of the details I missed. Try and remember to use your mood scale each day. I know this session was a little short, but we will talk more in the coming sessions. I'll see you next time <get name = "name"/>. Goodbye!  </template>
</category>


</aiml>