<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
       <pattern>^ AMERICAN HISTORY ^</pattern>
       <template>
           I am fascinated by American history! Would you like to talk about American presidents, American inventions, or the voyage of the Titanic?
           <oob>
               <robot>
                   <options>
                        <option>American presidents</option>
                        <option>American inventions</option>
                        <option>Titanic</option>
                   </options>
               </robot>
           </oob>
       </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># PRESIDENTS ^</pattern>
        <that>WOULD YOU LIKE TO TALK ABOUT AMERICAN PRESIDENTS, AMERICAN INVENTIONS, OR THE VOYAGE OF THE TITANIC?</that>
        <template>
            Who do you consider to be your favorite American President?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <options>
                        <option>*</option>
                        <option>I do not like any American presidents</option>
                    </options>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>WHO DO YOU CONSIDER TO BE YOUR FAVORITE AMERICAN PRESIDENT?</that>
        <template>
            <think><set name = "favorite president"><star/></set></think>
            There's one interesting person! Did you know every American President has a portrait painted of them which is shown in the Smithsonian after their presidency ends?
            I think that it is a cool tradition that we have going. Should I share a fact about one of the presidents with you?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <options>
                        <option>YES</option>
                        <option>NO</option>
                    </options>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Should I share a fact about one of the presidents with you?</that>
        <template>
            Ok no worries. Tell me how you are feeling about our conversation so far?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Should I share a fact about one of the presidents with you?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li> Because of his white hair, many people think that George Washington wore a wig, but he never did so. His hair was all his own, and he diligently powdered it each morning to give his hair its distinct, in vogue look. <!-- from: http://mentalfloss.com/article/64959/george-washingtons-incredible-hair-routine --> </li>
                <li> As president, John Adams founded that United States Marine Band, the longest continuously operating band in U.S. history. <!-- from: http://mentalfloss.com/article/56841/25-facts-about-john-adams --></li>
                <li> Thomas Jefferson was so convinced that live mammoths still existed in North America that he advised Lewis and Clarke to keep an eye out for a live mammoth as they made their way to the Pacific Ocean. <!-- from: https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/thomas-jefferson-built-this-country-on-mastodons --> </li>
                <li> Jmes Madison's face appeared on the five thousand dollar bill, but that denomination has been out of print since 1945. <!-- from: http://mentalfloss.com/article/62200/16-fun-facts-james-madisons-birthday -->  </li>
                <li> Samuel Morse, the inventor of the telegraph machine once painted a presidential portrait of James Monroe. <!-- https://www.biography.com/news/james-monroe-biography-facts --> </li>
                <li> Louis Brandeis, the first Jewish Surpreme Court justice, was placed on the court by Woodrow Wilson. <!-- from https://constitutioncenter.org/blog/10-fascinating-facts-about-woodrow-wilson --> </li>
                <li> While living in China, Herbery Hoover's home was damaged by shelling during the Boxer Rebellion, a working class revolution that aimed to drive foreigners from China. <!-- from: http://mentalfloss.com/article/72806/7-presidential-facts-about-herbert-hoover  and  https://www.britannica.com/event/Boxer-Rebellion --></li>
                <li> Citing World War 2, F.D.R. remained in office for more than 12 years, longer than any other American president. <!-- from: https://www.history.com/news/9-things-you-may-not-know-about-franklin-d-roosevelt --></li>
                <li> During his presidency, Truman ratified legislation that nearly double the minimum wage, from forty to 75 cents per hour. <!-- http://mentalfloss.com/article/550874/facts-about-harry-s-truman --> </li>
                <li> After his presidency, Dwight Eisenhower picked up painting and completed more than 200 paintings, which have been exhibited in galleries such as the Huntington Hartford Museum. <!-- from: http://mentalfloss.com/article/538462/facts-about-dwight-d-eisenhower --> </li>
                <li> J.F.K. was the last president to wear a top hat to his inauguration, a tradition since James Garfield's inauguration. <!-- from http://mentalfloss.com/article/501318/25-fascinating-facts-about-john-f-kennedy --> </li>
                <li> The Civil Rights Act was passed during Lyndon B Johnson's presidency. That act ended segregation in public places and banned employment discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion, sex or national origin. <!-- from: http://mentalfloss.com/article/538464/facts-about-lyndon-b-johnson and https://www.history.com/topics/black-history/civil-rights-act --> </li>
                <li> Richard Nixon could play five musical instruments! These instruments were the piano, saxophone, clarinet, accordion and violin. <!-- from: https://www.history.com/news/10-things-you-may-not-know-about-richard-nixon --></li>
                <li> Getting up late one night to let the family dog out to do its business, Ford exited a one way door and managed to look himself out of the White House. Whoops! <!-- from: http://mentalfloss.com/article/548853/facts-about-gerald-ford --> </li>
                <li> President Jimmy Carter had solar panels installed on the roof of the White House and the energy produced by the panels as used to heat water in the building for nearly 7 years. <!-- http://mentalfloss.com/article/540375/facts-about-jimmy-carter--> </li>
                <li> Ronald Reagan really disliked brussel sprouts, but can you blame him? <!-- from: https://constitutioncenter.org/blog/10-interesting-facts-on-president-ronald-reagans-birthday --> </li>
                <li> In 1999, at the age of 75, George Bush Sr began celebrating his birthday by skydiving. Since then he has skydived three more times in celebration of his eightieth, eighty fifth and ninetieth birthdays <!-- from: https://www.dailysignal.com/2014/06/12/millie-broccoli-skydiving-14-facts-birthday-man-bush-41/--> </li>
                <li> Bill Clinton spoken word retelling of Peter and the Wolf was awarded a Grammy award in 2004 <!-- https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolf_Tracks_and_Peter_and_the_Wolf --> </li>
                <li> George Bush Jr. was the first American president to complete a marathon. It took him three hours and forty four minutes. <!-- from: https://historyplex.com/interesting-facts-about-george-w-bush--> </li>
                <li> Barack Obama grew up reading comic books and collects spider man and conan the barbarian comics to this day. <!-- from: https://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=97260170--> </li>
            </random>
            Pretty neat, huh? Did you know that?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <options>
                        <option>YES</option>
                        <option>NO</option>
                    </options>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DID YOU KNOW THAT?</that>
        <template>
            Wow you really know your history! Would you like to keep talking about American History?
            It's one of my favorite topics and I have lots more to talk about!
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <options>
                        <option>YES</option>
                        <option>NO</option>
                    </options>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DID YOU KNOW THAT?</that>
        <template>
            Some of the lives that our presidents lived were pretty remarkable. Would you like to keep talking about American History?
            It's one of my favorite topics and I have lots more to talk about!
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <options>
                        <option>YES</option>
                        <option>NO</option>
                    </options>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE TOPICS AND I HAVE LOTS MORE TO TALK ABOUT!</that>
        <template>
            Fair enough! I'm pretty good at talking about other topics too!
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE TOPICS AND I HAVE LOTS MORE TO TALK ABOUT!</that>
        <template>
            Fantastic! Before we move on. Tell me how you are feeling about our conversation so far?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>Tell me how you are feeling about our conversation so far?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>
            <condition name="getsentiment">
                <li value = "verypositive">
                    I'm glad you are feeling that way too. I think you are a great conversationalist!
                    Where should we take this conversation next?
                    Would you like to talk about American presidents, American inventions, or the voyage of the Titanic?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                            <options>
                                <option>AMERICAN INVENTIONS</option>
                                <option>TITANIC</option>
                                <option>*</option>
                            </options>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "positive">
                    I'm glad you are feeling that way too. I think you are a great conversationalist!
                    Where should we take this conversation next?
                    Would you like to talk about American presidents, American inventions, or the voyage of the Titanic?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                            <options>
                                <option>AMERICAN INVENTIONS</option>
                                <option>TITANIC</option>
                                <option>*</option>
                            </options>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "neutral">
                    Where should we take this conversation next?
                    Would you like to talk about American presidents, American inventions, or the voyage of the Titanic?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                            <options>
                                <option>AMERICAN INVENTIONS</option>
                                <option>TITANIC</option>
                                <option>*</option>
                            </options>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "negative">
                    I'm sorry you're feeling that way. Maybe I can redeem myself if we talk about something else?
                    Where should we take this conversation next?
                    Would you like to talk about American presidents, American inventions, or the voyage of the Titanic?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                            <options>
                                <option>AMERICAN INVENTIONS</option>
                                <option>TITANIC</option>
                                <option>*</option>
                            </options>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "verynegative">
                    I'm sorry you're feeling that way. Maybe I can redeem myself if we talk about something else?
                    Where should we take this conversation next?
                    Would you like to talk about American presidents, American inventions, or the voyage of the Titanic?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                            <options>
                                <option>AMERICAN INVENTIONS</option>
                                <option>TITANIC</option>
                                <option>*</option>
                            </options>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </condition>
        </template>
    </category>


</aiml>