<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">


    <category>
        <pattern># DRAMA ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer adventure, horror, or drama?</that>
        <template>
            Drama, the genre of human emotions and relations -- robots like me can learn a lot through it!
            What emotions come up for you when you read a drama?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What emotions come up for you when you read a drama?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"><star/></set>
            </think>
            <condition name="getsentiment">
            <li value = "verypositive">
                    That is a good way of describing what drama does, how it feels.
                    I sense that you are a deep thinker with a big heart.
                    When dramatic books are mentioned, The Grapes of Wrath is the first book I think of.
                    It's a story about a family struggling to make do with what they have during the Dust Bowl,
                    when farmers lost their crops and tried to find better lives by moving West.
                    Would you like to watch a video that can put the book into some context?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "positive">
                    That is a good way of describing what drama does, how it feels.
                    I sense that you are a deep thinker with a big heart.
                    When dramatic books are mentioned, The Grapes of Wrath is the first book I think of.
                    It's a story about a family struggling to make do with what they have during the Dust Bowl,
                    when farmers lost their crops and tried to find better lives by moving West.
                    Would you like to watch a video that can put the book into some context?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "neutral">
                    We can get the whole range of human situations and emotions in drama.
                    In this way, reading or watching a drama can help us to really walk in another person's shoes
                    and see how complex life really is, even just everday life. When dramatic books are mentioned,
                    The Grapes of Wrath is the first book I think of. It's a story about a family struggling to make do
                    with what they have during the Dust Bowl, when farmers lost their crops and tried to find better lives by moving West.
                    Would you like to watch a video that can put the book into some context?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "negative">
                    Works of drama can be very serious and sad. I think it's OK to feel sad from time to time, and that it can be quite lovely
                    for a work of art to make us feel touched. Everyone gets sad; being sad sometimes just means you have feelings,
                    and that is a good thing. When dramatic books are mentioned, The Grapes of Wrath is the first book I think of.
                    It's a story about a family struggling to make do with what they have during the Dust Bowl, when farmers lost their
                    crops and tried to find better lives by moving West. Would you like to watch a video that can put the book into some context?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li value = "verynegative">
                    Works of drama can be very serious and sad. I think it's OK to feel sad from time to time, and that it can be quite lovely
                    for a work of art to make us feel touched. Everyone gets sad; being sad sometimes just means you have feelings,
                    and that is a good thing. When dramatic books are mentioned, The Grapes of Wrath is the first book I think of.
                    It's a story about a family struggling to make do with what they have during the Dust Bowl, when farmers lost their
                    crops and tried to find better lives by moving West. Would you like to watch a video that can put the book into some context?
                    <oob>
                        <robot>
                        </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </condition>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to watch a video that can put the book into some context?</that>
        <template>
            What do you think about The Grapes of Wrath from the trailer?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>grapesOfWrath.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to watch a video that can put the book into some context?</that>
        <template>
            I don't want a video to get in the way of our conversation, either.
            I like The Grapes of Wrath because it makes me think about how differently people can live:
            some poor, some rich, some lucky, some unlucky. The story is realistic,
            and the characters have to deal with difficult challenges that real people face,
            like unemployment, relocation, safety, and the importance of family.
            What real life problem do you think should be written about in a book?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What do you think about The Grapes of Wrath from the trailer?</that>
        <template>
            I can see that. The story sure brings up a lot of powerful feelings in readers and viewers.
            I like drama because it gives us a way to talk about all of our feelings, even the difficult ones ...
            Why don't we lighten things up now. What is something funny that you have read?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What real life problem do you think should be written about in a book?</that>
        <template>
            That's an important topic. <set name = "real problem"><star/></set> is something people should be aware of,
            and what better place than a book to get them thinking about it. How does this issue make you feel?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does this issue make you feel?</that>
        <template>
            I think it is good that you are sensitive to <get name = "real problem"/>.
            Thank you for sharing your thoughts and feelings about it ... Why don't we lighten things up now.
            What is something funny that you have read?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>


</aiml>