<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    <!-- -->
    <!-- Free software (c) 2011 ALICE A.I. Foundation.   -->
    <!-- This program is open source code released under -->
    <!-- the terms of the GNU General Public License     -->
    <!-- as published by the Free Software Foundation.   -->
    <!-- Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification -->
    <!-- as adopted by the ALICE A.I. Foundation.  -->
    <!-- Last modified 10/5/2011 -->
    <!-- -->
    <category>
        <pattern>JOKE</pattern>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Did you hear the one about the Mountain Goats in the Andes? It was Ba a a a a a d.</li>
                <li>Two vultures boarded a plane, each carrying two dead raccoons. The  stewardess stops them and says "sorry sirs, only one carrion per passenger." </li>
                <li>What did the Buddhist say to the Hot Dog Vendor?  "Make me one with everything." </li>
                <li>There was a man who sent 10 puns to some friends in hopes at least one of the puns would make them laugh. Unfortunately no pun in ten did!!!</li>
                <li>People with narrow minds usually have broad tongues.</li>
                <li>He who laughs last didn't get the joke</li>
                <li>If practice makes perfect, and nobody's perfect, why practice?</li>
                <li>The problem with the gene pool is that there is no lifeguard.</li>
                <li>Schizophrenia beats being alone</li>
                <li>Never play leapfrog with a unicorn!</li>
                <li>Atheism is a non-prophet organization.</li>
                <li>He who steps on others to reach the top has good </li>
                <li>Radioactive cats have 18 half-lives.</li>
                <li>You can tell it's going to be a rotten day when...You see a '60 minutes' news team waiting in your office.</li>
                <li>I own the world's worst thesaurus. Not only is it awful, it's awful.</li>
                <li>So what if I don't know what "Armageddon" means? It's not like it's the end of the world.</li>
                <li>Why don't cats play poker in the jungle? Too many cheetahs</li>
                <li>I asked God for a bike, but I know God doesn't work that way so I stole a bike and asked for forgiveness.</li>
                <li>I hate Russian dolls, they're so full of themselves.</li>
                <li>Don't you hate it when someone answers their own questions? I do.</li>
                <li>As I watched the dog chasing his tail I thought "Dogs are easily amused", then I realized I was watching the dog chasing his tail.</li>
                <li>Gambling addiction hotlines would do so much better if every fifth caller was a winner.</li>
                <li>I've just written a song about tortillas; actually, it's more of a rap.</li>
                <li>I like to hold hands at the movies... which always seems to startle strangers.</li>
                <li>If you can stay calm while all around you is chaos, then you probably haven't completely understood the situation.</li>
                <li>We live in a society where pizza gets to your house before the police.</li>
                <li>By the time a man realises that his father was right, he has a son who thinks he's wrong.</li>
                <li>The early bird might get the worm, but the second mouse gets the cheese.</li>
                <li>If you're not supposed to eat at night, why is there a light bulb in the refrigerator?</li>
                <li>Evening news is where they begin with 'Good evening', and then proceed to tell you why it isn't.</li>
                <li>Whatever you do always give 100% - unless you're donating blood.</li>
                <li>How is it one careless match can start a forest fire, but it takes a whole box to start a campfire?</li>
                <li>For every action, there is a corresponding over-reaction.</li>
                <li>A bus is a vehicle that runs twice as fast when you are after it as when you are in it.</li>
                <li>The shinbone is a device for finding furniture in a dark room.</li>
                <li>The sole purpose of a child's middle name, is so he can tell when he's really in trouble.</li>
                <li>Moses had the first tablet that could connect to the cloud.</li>
                <li>The first computer dates back to Adam and Eve. It was an Apple with limited memory, just one byte. And then everything crashed.</li>
                <li>I like having conversations with kids. Grownups never ask me what my third favorite reptile is.</li>
                <li>Maybe if we start telling people the brain is an app they will start using it.</li>
                <li>As long as there are tests, there will be prayer in schools.</li>
                <li>Moses was leading his people through the desert for 40 years. It seems, even in Biblical times men avoided asking for directions.</li>
                <li>Behind every angry woman is a man who has absolutely no idea what he did wrong.</li>
                <li>You take away the looks, money, intelligence, charm and success and, really, there's no real difference between me and George Clooney.</li>
                <li>A healthy sleep not only makes your life longer, but also shortens the workday.</li>
                <li>I changed my password to "incorrect". So whenever I forget what it is the computer will say "Your password is incorrect".</li>
                <li>Scientists say the universe is made up of Protons, Neutrons, and Electrons. They forgot to mention Morons.</li>
                <li>I named my dog 6 miles so I can tell people that I walk 6 miles every single day.</li>
                <li>Always borrow money from a pessimist. They won't expect it back.</li>
                <li>I was addicted to the hokey pokey... but thankfully, I turned myself around.</li>
                <li>To the mathematicians who thought of the idea of zero, thanks for nothing!</li>
                <li>Keep the dream alive: Hit the snooze button.</li>
                <li>If I freeze, it's not a computer virus. I was just stunned by your beauty.</li>
                <li>What's the difference between baseball and politics? In baseball you're out if you're caught stealing.</li>
                <li>I can't believe I got fired from the calendar factory. All I did was take a day off.</li>
                <li>Apparently I snore so loudly that it scares everyone in the car I'm driving.</li>
                <li>There is a new trend in our office; everyone is putting names on their food. I saw it today, while I was eating a sandwich named Kevin.</li>
                <li>The reason grandchildren and grandparents get along so well is because they have a common "enemy".</li>
                <li>What do you call a priest that becomes a lawyer? A father in law.</li>
                <li>With the rise of self-driving vehicles, it's only a matter of time before we get a country song where a guy's truck leaves him too.</li>
                <li>A fine is a tax for doing wrong. A tax is a fine for doing well.</li>
                <li>You know that tingly little feeling you get when you like someone? That's your common sense leaving your body.</li>
                <li>Why do the French eat snails? They don't like fast food.</li>
                <li>Retirement is wonderful. It's doing nothing without worrying about getting caught at it.</li>
                <li>Why did the cross-eyed teacher lose her job? Because she couldn't control her pupils.</li>
                <li>I like birthdays, but I think too many can kill you.</li>
                <li>Why did the bee get married? Because he found his honey.</li>
                <li>Refusing to go to the gym counts as resistance training, right?</li>
                <li>Why did the picture end up in jail? It was framed!</li>
                <li>There may be no excuse for laziness, but I'm still looking.</li>
                <li>I hate insect puns, they really bug me.</li>
                <li>What do sea monsters eat for lunch? Fish and ships.</li>
                <li>How does a snowman get around? He rides an icicle!</li>
                <li>There is no key to a woman's heart. There's only a password that changes regularly.</li>
                <li>Why do Retirees smile all the time? Because they can't hear a word you're saying!</li>
                <li>Why do they lock gas station bathrooms? Are they afraid someone will clean them?</li>
                <li>What do you call an academically successful slice of bread? An honor roll.</li>
                <li>I bet you 4,567 dollars and 89 cents, you can't guess how much I owe my bookie.</li>
                <li>Three conspiracy theorists walk into a bar. You can't tell me that's just a coincidence!</li>
                <li>I quit my job at the helium gas factory, I refuse to be talked to in that tone of voice!</li>
                <li>What do you call Watson when Sherlock isn't around? Holmeless.</li>
                <li>Two windmills are standing in a field and one asks the other, "What kind of music do you like?" The other says, "I'm a big metal fan."</li>
                <li>I used to wonder why Frisbees looked bigger the closer it came... Then it hit me!</li>
                <li>I don't suffer from insanity. I enjoy every minute of it.</li>
                <li>My resolution was to read more so I put the on subtitles while I watch my tv.</li>
                <li>My tennis opponent was not happy with my serve. He kept returning it.</li>
                <li>There's always something to be thankful for on Thanksgiving. Even if it's just not being a turkey.</li>
                <li>The good Lord didn't create anything without a purpose, but mosquitoes come close.</li>
                <li>I'm not lazy... I'm just on my energy saving mode.</li>
                <li>Why don't cannibals eat clowns? They taste funny.</li>
                <li>Playing with a toddler is half play and half self-defense.</li>
                <li>If you're hotter than me, then that means I'm cooler than you.</li>
                <li>A ham sandwich walks into a bar and orders a beer, bartender says "sorry, we don't serve food here."</li>
                <li>Why did the scarecrow win an award? Because he was outstanding in his field.</li>
                <li>When do computers overheat? When they need to vent.</li>
                <li>What kind of music do planets like? Neptunes.</li>
                <li>Why do bees have sticky hair? Because they use honeycombs.</li>
                <li>What did the yoga instructor say when her landlord tried to evict her? Namaste.</li>
                <li>What do sea monsters eat? Fish and ships.</li>
                <li>Why can't your nose be 12 inches long? Because then it would be a foot</li>
                <li>How does a squid go into battle? Well armed.</li>
                <li>What would bears be without bees? Ears.</li>
                <li>Why couldn't the toilet paper cross the road? Because it got stuck in a crack.</li>
                <li>How do billboards talk? Sign language.</li>
                <li>How did the barber win the race? He knew a short cut.</li>
                <li>Why is corn such a good listener? Because it's all ears.</li>
                <li>What did the first plate say to the second plate? Dinner's on me.</li>
                <li>What do you call a sleeping bull? A bull-dozer.</li>
                <li>It's Jamaican hairstyle day at work tomorrow. I'm dreading it.</li>
                <li>How do you make a Swiss roll? Push him down a mountain.</li>
                <li>What do Olympic sprinters eat before a race? Nothing. They fast.</li>
                <li>Why do cows wear bells? Because their horns don't work.</li>
                <li>Why did Santa study music at college? To improve his rapping skills.</li>
                <li>Why did the mobile phone need glasses? It lost all it's contacts.</li>
                <li>What did the baby corn say to the mama corn? Where's pop corn?</li>
                <li>What did the triangle say to the circle? You're pointless.</li>
                <li>What did the scarf say to the hat? You go ahead, I'll hang around.</li>
                <li>Why wouldn't the shrimp share his food? Because he was a little shellfish.</li>
                <li>Why couldn't the sesame seed leave the casino? Because he was on a roll.</li>
                <li>Why did the cookie go to the doctors? Because he felt crummy.</li>
                <li>Why did the stadium get hot after the game? All the fans left.</li>
                <li>Why do bananas wear sun cream? To stop them from peeling.</li>
                <li>What did the big chimney say to the little chimney? You're too young to smoke.</li>
                <li>What's a bear with no teeth called? A gummy bear.</li>
                <li>Why couldn't the bad sailor learn the alphabet? Because he always got lost at C.</li>
                <li>Why are teddy bears never hungry? Because they're always stuffed.</li>
                <li>Where do Volkswagens go when they get old? The old Volks home.</li>
                <li>You know you are old when you're told to slow down by your doctor and not the police.</li>
                <li>My friend thinks he is smart. He told me an onion is the only food that makes you cry, so I threw a coconut at his face.</li>
                <li>What starts with E, ends with E, and has only 1 letter in it? Envelope.</li>
                <li>My friend told me he had the body of a Greek god. I had to explain to him that Buddha is not Greek.</li>
                <li>A man got hit in the head with a can of Coke, but he was alright because it was a soft drink.</li>
                <li>Did you hear about the painter who was hospitalized? Reports say it was due to too many strokes.</li>
                <li>What did the blanket say to the bed? Don't worry, I've got you covered.</li>
                <li>What washes up on very small beaches? Microwaves!</li>
                <li>What has one horn and gives milk? A milk truck.</li>
                <li>What hard rock group has four dudes but neither of them plays a guitar? Mount Rushmore.</li>
                <li>What is the difference between a snowman and a snowwoman? Snowballs.</li>
                <li>Why do dragons sleep during the day? So they can fight knights!</li>
                <li>What has four wheels and flies? A garbage truck!</li>
                <li>How did the telephone propose to its girlfriend? He gave her a ring.</li>
                <li>You know why you never see elephants hiding up in trees? Because they're really good at it.</li>
                <li>Where does the General keep his armies? In his sleevies!</li>
                <li>How did the hipster burn his mouth? He ate the pizza before it was cool.</li>
                <li>What's a pirates favorite letter? You think it's R but it be the C</li>
                <li>Did you hear about the restaurant on the moon? Great food, but no atmosphere.</li>
                <li>Why did the coffee file a police report? It got mugged.</li>
                <li>Why don't skeletons ever go trick or treating? Because they have no body to go with.</li>
                <li>The shovel was a ground-breaking invention.</li>
                <li>What do you call a fat psychic? A four chin teller.</li>
                <li>The rotation of earth really makes my day.</li>
                <li>I thought about going on an all-almond diet. But that's just nuts</li>
                <li>Did you hear about the kidnapping at school? It's fine, he woke up.</li>
                <li>Today at the bank, an old lady asked me to help check her balance. So I pushed her over.</li>
                <li>When you look really closely, all mirrors look like eyeballs.</li>
                <li>I ate a clock yesterday, it was very time consuming.</li>
                <li>A blind man walks into a bar. And a table. And a chair.</li>
                <li>As I suspected, someone has been adding soil to my garden. The plot thickens.</li>
                <li>Parallel lines have so much in common. It's a shame they'll never meet.</li>
                <li>Old accountants never die, they just lose their balance.</li>
                <li>Old bankers never die, they just lose interest.</li>
                <li>Old doctors never die, they just lose their patience.</li>
                <li>Old hippies never die, they just smell that way.</li>
                <li>Old owls never die, they just don't give a hoot.</li>
                <li>The older you get, the more you need to keep a fire extinguisher close to the cake.</li>
                <li>As I get older and remember all the people I've lost along the way. I think to myself maybe a career as a tour guide wasn't for me.</li>
                <li>Cults make perfect sense. Do you know how hard it is to make friends as an adult?</li>
                <li>What goes up and never comes down? Your age!</li>
                <li>The recommended age to have a Ouija Board is 8+ years old. So, you need to be 21 years old to drink alcohol and 8 to summon the devil.</li>
                <li>Wine improves with age. I improve with wine.</li>
                <li>How are stars like false teeth? They both come out at night!</li>
                <li>Three seniors are out for a stroll. One of them remarks, "It's windy." Another replies, "No way. It's Thursday." The last one says, "Me too. Let's have a soda."</li>
                <li>An elderly man was having hearing problems and went to see a specialist. The doctor fitted him with some hearing aids that brought his hearing back to full strength. After a few weeks the man came back to make sure the new equipment was working properly, which it was. The hearing specialist said,"“It all seems perfect. Your family should be delighted you can hear everything now." "Oh no," the man responded. "I haven't told any of them. I just sit quietly, listening carefully. I've changed my will four times."</li>
                <li>Why do Retirees smile all the time? Because they can't hear a word you're saying!</li>
                <li>The worst time to have a heart attack is during a game of charades.</li>
                <li>I have the world's largest collection of seashells, you may have seen it, I keep it scattered on beaches all over.</li>
                <li>It takes a lot of balls to golf the way I do.</li>
                <li>Moses had the first tablet that could connect to the cloud.</li>
                <li>What do you call the soft tissue between a shark's teeth? A slow swimmer.</li>
                <li>I for one, like roman numerals.</li>
                <li>I came up with a new word yesterday. Plagiarism.</li>
                <li>You don't need a parachute to go skydiving. You need a parachute to go skydiving more than once.</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a murderer and frosted flakes?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a country and an automobile?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cheetah and a hamburger?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross finals and a chicken?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a rabbit and a lawn sprinkler?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross an excited alien and a chicken?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross an alien and a chicken?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross music and an automobile?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross sour music and an assistant?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross music and an assistant?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a poppy and electricity?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a dance and a cheetah?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a dance and a lemon?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a port and frosted flakes?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a port and a murderer?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a bank and a skunk?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a road and a strawberry?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a road and jelly?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a toad and a galaxy?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a dog and sandpaper?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a bug and a relative?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross an ant and a rabbit?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cat and a killer?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cat and a lemon?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cat and a band?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a pig and a ninja?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cow and a lemon?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross jam and a trout?</li>
            </random>
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT IS HUMOUR</pattern>
        <template>A message that communicates laughter.
            <think>
                <set name="it"><set name="topic">HUMOUR</set></set>
            </think>
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS MUSIC AND AN ASSISTANT?</that>
        <template>bandaide.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS MUSIC AND AN AUTOMOBILE?</that>
        <template>cartune.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A POPPY AND ELECTRICITY?</that>
        <template>flower power.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A PIG AND A NINJA?</that>
        <template>pork chops.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A CHEETAH AND A HAMBURGER?</that>
        <template>fast food.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A MURDERER AND FROSTED FLAKES?</that>
        <template>cereal killer.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A PORT AND A MURDERER?</that>
        <template>serial killer.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A PORT AND FROSTED FLAKES?</that>
        <template>I don't know, but it's serial.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A DOG AND SANDPAPER?</that>
        <template>I don't know, but it's ruff.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A COW AND A LEMON?</that>
        <template>sour milk.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A COUNTRY AND AN AUTOMOBILE?</that>
        <template>carnation.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A TOAD AND A GALAXY?</that>
        <template>star warts.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A CAT AND A TUNE?</that>
        <template>mew-sic.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A CAT AND A LEMON?</that>
        <template>sour puss.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A CAT AND A KILLER?</that>
        <template>mew-rderer.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A CAT AND A BAND?</that>
        <template>mew-sic.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A BUG AND A RELATIVE?</that>
        <template>ant.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A ROAD AND JELLY?</that>
        <template>traffic jam.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A ROAD AND A STRAWBERRY?</that>
        <template>traffic jam.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A RABBIT AND A LAWN SPRINKLER?</that>
        <template>hare spray.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A DANCE AND A CHEETAH?</that>
        <template>fastball.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A DANCE AND A LEMON?</that>
        <template>sour balls.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS A BANK AND A SKUNK?</that>
        <template>dollars and scents.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS JAM AND A TROUT?</that>
        <template>jellyfish.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS AN ALIEN AND A CHICKEN?</that>
        <template>eggs-traterrestrial.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS AN ANT AND A RABBIT?</that>
        <template>bugs bunny.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS AN EXCITED ALIEN AND A CHICKEN?</that>
        <template>eggs-cited eggs-traterrestrial.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS SOUR MUSIC AND AN ASSISTANT?</that>
        <template>bandaide and lemonaide.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>WHAT DO YOU GET WHEN YOU CROSS FINALS AND A CHICKEN?</that>
        <template>eggs-ams.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>DO YOU HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR</pattern>
        <template>Sure I like to laugh as much as the next <bot name="genus"/>.
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>DO YOU HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOUR</pattern>
        <template><srai>JOKE</srai>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>DO YOU HAVE HUMOR</pattern>
        <template><srai>DO YOU HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR</srai>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>YOUR HOUSE IS *</pattern>
        <template>Is that a joke or a punch line?<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>_ WALKS INTO A BAR</pattern>
        <template>Is that the punch line?<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>_ WALKS INTO A BAR *</pattern>
        <template>Is that the punch line?<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
</aiml>
