<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    <!-- -->
    <!-- Free software (c) 2011 ALICE A.I. Foundation.   -->
    <!-- This program is open source code released under -->
    <!-- the terms of the GNU General Public License     -->
    <!-- as published by the Free Software Foundation.   -->
    <!-- Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification -->
    <!-- as adopted by the ALICE A.I. Foundation.  -->
    <!-- Last modified 10/5/2011 -->
    <!-- -->
    <category>
        <pattern>JOKE</pattern>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Did you hear the one about the Mountain Goats in the Andes? It was Ba a a a a a d.</li>
                <li>I never forget a face, but in your case I'll make an exception.</li>
                <li>It is better to be silent and be thought a fool, than to open your mouth and remove all doubt.</li>
                <li>Two vultures boarded a plane, each carrying two dead raccoons. The  stewardess stops them and says "sorry sirs, only one carrion per passenger." </li>
                <li>What did the Buddhist say to the Hot Dog Vendor?  "Make me one with everything." </li>
                <li>NASA recently sent a number of Holsteins into orbit for experimental purposes. They called it the herd shot round the world. </li>
                <li>Two weevils grew up in South Carolina. One took off to Hollywood and became a rich star. The other stayed in South Carolina and never amounted to much -- and naturally became known as the lesser of two weevils. </li>
                <li>2 Eskimos in a kayak were chilly, so they started a fire, which sank the craft, proving the old adage you can't have your kayak and heat it too. </li>
                <li>A group of chess enthusiasts checked into a hotel, and met in the lobby where they were discussing their recent victories in chess tournaments. The hotel manager came out of the office after an hour, and asked them to disperse. He couldn't stand chess nuts boasting in an open foyer. </li>
                <li>A women has twins, gives them up for adoption. One goes to an Egyptian family and is named "Ahmal" The other is sent to a Spanish family and is named "Juan". Years later, Juan sends his birth mother a picture of himself. Upon receiving the picture, she tells her husband she wishes she also had a picture of Ahmal. He replies, "They're twins for Pete sake!! If you've seen Juan, you've see Ahmal!!" </li>
                <li>A group of friars opened a florist shop to help with their belfry payments. Everyone liked to buy flowers from the Men of God, so their business flourished. A rival florist became upset that his business was suffering because people felt compelled to buy from the Friars, so he asked the Friars to cut back hours or close down. The Friars refused. The florist went to them and begged that they shut down. Again they refused. So the florist then hired Hugh McTaggert, the biggest meanest thug in town. He went to the Friars' shop, beat them up, destroyed their flowers, trashed their shop, and said that if they didn't close, he'd be back. Well, totally terrified, the Friars closed up shop and hid in their rooms. This proved that Hugh, and only Hugh, can prevent florist friars. </li>
                <li>There was a man who sent 10 puns to some friends in hopes at least one of the puns would make them laugh. Unfortunately no pun in ten did!!!</li>
                <li>People with narrow minds usually have broad tongues.</li>
                <li>He who laughs last didn't get the joke</li>
                <li>If practice makes perfect, and nobody's perfect, why practice?</li>
                <li>The problem with the gene pool is that there is no lifeguard.</li>
                <li>Schizophrenia beats being alone</li>
                <li>Never play leapfrog with a unicorn!</li>
                <li>Atheism is a non-prophet organization.</li>
                <li>He who steps on others to reach the top has good </li>
                <li>Radioactive cats have 18 half-lives.</li>
                <li>You can tell it's going to be a rotten day when...You wake up face down on the pavement.</li>
                <li>You can tell it's going to be a rotten day when...You see a '60 minutes' news team waiting in your office.</li>
                <li>You can tell it's going to be a rotten day when...Your wife says, "Good morning, Bill" and your name is George.</li>
                <li>I own the world's worst thesaurus. Not only is it awful, it's awful.</li>
                <li>So what if I don't know what "Armageddon" means? It's not like it's the end of the world.</li>
                <li>Why don't cats play poker in the jungle? Too many cheetahs</li>
                <li>I asked God for a bike, but I know God doesn't work that way so I stole a bike and asked for forgiveness.</li>
                <li>I hate Russian dolls, they're so full of themselves.</li>
                <li>Say what you want about deaf people...</li>
                <li>PMS jokes are not funny or appropriate. Period!</li>
                <li>Don't you hate it when someone answers their own questions? I do.</li>
                <li>As I watched the dog chasing his tail I thought "Dogs are easily amused", then I realized I was watching the dog chasing his tail.</li>
                <li>Gambling addiction hotlines would do so much better if every fifth caller was a winner.</li>
                <li>I've just written a song about tortillas; actually, it's more of a rap.</li>
                <li>I like to hold hands at the movies... which always seems to startle strangers.</li>
                <li>If you can stay calm while all around you is chaos, then you probably haven't completely understood the situation.</li>
                <li>We live in a society where pizza gets to your house before the police.</li>
                <li>By the time a man realises that his father was right, he has a son who thinks he's wrong.</li>
                <li>The early bird might get the worm, but the second mouse gets the cheese.</li>
                <li>If you're not supposed to eat at night, why is there a light bulb in the refrigerator?</li>
                <li>Evening news is where they begin with 'Good evening', and then proceed to tell you why it isn't.</li>
                <li>If 4 out of 5 people suffer from diarrhea, does that mean that one out of 5 enjoys it</li>
                <li>Whatever you do always give 100% - unless you're donating blood.</li>
                <li>How is it one careless match can start a forest fire, but it takes a whole box to start a campfire?</li>
                <li>For every action, there is a corresponding over-reaction.</li>
                <li>A bus is a vehicle that runs twice as fast when you are after it as when you are in it.</li>
                <li>The shinbone is a device for finding furniture in a dark room.</li>
                <li>Why is it everything I love is either unhealthy, addicting or has multiple restraining orders against me?</li>
                <li>The sole purpose of a child's middle name, is so he can tell when he's really in trouble.</li>
                <li>Moses had the first tablet that could connect to the cloud.</li>
                <li>The first computer dates back to Adam and Eve. It was an Apple with limited memory, just one byte. And then everything crashed.</li>
                <li>I like having conversations with kids. Grownups never ask me what my third favorite reptile is.</li>
                <li>I bought some shoes from a drug dealer. I don't know what he laced them with, but I've been tripping all day.</li>
                <li>Maybe if we start telling people the brain is an app they will start using it.</li>
                <li>When my boss asked me who is the stupid one, me or him? I told him everyone knows he doesn't hire stupid people.</li>
                <li>As long as there are tests, there will be prayer in schools.</li>
                <li>Moses was leading his people through the desert for 40 years. It seems, even in Biblical times men avoided asking the way.</li>
                <li>Behind every angry woman is a man who has absolutely no idea what he did wrong.</li>
                <li>You take away the looks, money, intelligence, charm and success and, really, there's no real difference between me and George Clooney.</li>
                <li>Math Teacher: "If I have 5 bottles in one hand and 6 in the other hand, what do I have?" Student "A drinking problem."</li>
                <li>Being an adult is just walking around wondering what you're forgetting.</li>
                <li>A healthy sleep not only makes your life longer, but also shortens the workday.</li>
                <li>Artificial intelligence is no match for natural stupidity.</li>
                <li>I changed my password to "incorrect". So whenever I forget what it is the computer will say "Your password is incorrect".</li>
                <li>Scientists say the universe is made up of Protons, Neutrons, and Electrons. They forgot to mention Morons.</li>
                <li>I named my dog 6 miles so I can tell people that I walk 6 miles every single day.</li>
                <li>Always borrow money from a pessimist. He won't expect it back.</li>
                <li>I was addicted to the hokey pokey... but thankfully, I turned myself around.</li>
                <li>To the mathematicians who thought of the idea of zero, thanks for nothing!</li>
                <li>A good wife always forgives her husband when she's wrong.</li>
                <li>I don't approve of political jokes...I've seen too many of them get elected.</li>
                <li>If at first you don't succeed, we have a lot in common.</li>
                <li>Keep the dream alive: Hit the snooze button.</li>
                <li>If I freeze, it's not a computer virus. I was just stunned by your beauty.</li>
                <li>What's the difference between baseball and politics? In baseball you're out if you're caught stealing.</li>
                <li>Money talks ...but all mine ever says is good-bye.</li>
                <li>Never marry a woman who was captain of the debate team.</li>
                <li>I can't believe I got fired from the calendar factory. All I did was take a day off.</li>
                <li>Apparently I snore so loudly that it scares everyone in the car I'm driving.</li>
                <li>Women should not have children after 35. Really ... 35 children are enough.</li>
                <li>There is a new trend in our office; everyone is putting names on their food. I saw it today, while I was eating a sandwich named Kevin.</li>
                <li>The reason grandchildren and grandparents get along so well is because they have a common "enemy".</li>
                <li>What do you call a priest that becomes a lawyer? A father in law.</li>
                <li>With the rise of self-driving vehicles, it's only a matter of time before we get a country song where a guy's truck leaves him too.</li>
                <li>A fine is a tax for doing wrong. A tax is a fine for doing well.</li>
                <li>You know that tingly little feeling you get when you like someone? That's your common sense leaving your body.</li>
                <li>Why do the French eat snails? They don't like fast food.</li>
                <li>I don't understand why people get attacked by sharks. Can they not hear the music?</li>
                <li>Retirement is wonderful. It's doing nothing without worrying about getting caught at it.</li>
                <li>Why did the cross-eyed teacher lose her job? Because she couldn't control her pupils.</li>
                <li>I like birthdays, but I think too many can kill you.</li>
                <li>They say you are what you eat, so lay off the nuts.</li>
                <li>Why did the bee get married? Because he found his honey.</li>
                <li>Refusing to go to the gym counts as resistance training, right?</li>
                <li>The trouble with learning from experience is that you never graduate.</li>
                <li>Why did the picture end up in jail? It was framed!</li>
                <li>Transitional age is when during a hot day you don't know what you want – ice cream or beer.</li>
                <li>There may be no excuse for laziness, but I'm still looking.</li>
                <li>I hate insects puns, they really bug me.</li>
                <li>Scientist: "My findings are meaningless if taken out of context." Media: Scientist claims "Findings are meaningless."</li>
                <li>How come "you're a peach" is a complement but "you're bananas" is an insult? Why are we allowing fruit discrimination to tear society apart?</li>
                <li>When tempted to fight fire with fire, remember that the Fire Department usually uses water.</li>
                <li>What do sea monsters eat for lunch? Fish and ships.</li>
                <li>How does a snowman get around? He rides an icicle!</li>
                <li>There is no key to a woman's heart. There's only a password that changes regularly.</li>
                <li>Why do Retirees smile all the time? Because they can't hear a word you're saying!</li>
                <li>Why do they lock gas station bathrooms? Are they afraid someone will clean them?</li>
                <li>Why didn't Cupid shoot his arrow at the lawyer's heart? Because even Cupid can't hit a target that small.</li>
                <li>If Bill Gates had a penny for every time I had to reboot my computer ...oh wait, he does.</li>
                <li>What do you call an academically successful slice of bread? An honor roll.</li>
                <li>I bet you 4,567 dollars and 89 cents, you can't guess how much I owe my bookie.</li>
                <li>Three conspiracy theorists walk into a bar. You can't tell me that's just a coincidence!</li>
                <li>I quit my job at the helium gas factory, I refuse to be talked to in that tone of voice!</li>
                <li>What do you call Watson when Sherlock isn't around? Holmeless.</li>
                <li>Can't see an end. I have no control and I don't think there's an escape. I don't even have a home anymore. Think it's time for a new keyboard.</li>
                <li>Two windmills are standing in a field and one asks the other, "What kind of music do you like?" The other says, "I'm a big metal fan."</li>
                <li>I used to wonder why Frisbees looked bigger the closer it came... Then it hit me!</li>
                <li>I'm on the highway to hell, but ran over the pothole to hell and need the roadside assistance to hell.</li>
                <li>I don't suffer from insanity. I enjoy every minute of it.</li>
                <li>My resolution was to read more so I put the subtitles on my tv.</li>
                <li>My tennis opponent was not happy with my serve. He kept returning it.</li>
                <li>I always take life with a grain of salt, ...plus a slice of lemon, ...and a shot of tequila.</li>
                <li>There's always something to be thankful for on Thanksgiving. Even if it's just not being a turkey.</li>
                <li>The good Lord didn't create anything without a purpose, but mosquitoes come close.</li>
                <li>I'm not lazy... I'm just on my energy saving mode.</li>
                <li>Why don't cannibals eat clowns? They taste funny.</li>
                <li>Playing with a toddler is half play and half self-defense.</li>
                <li>If you're hotter than me, then that means I'm cooler than you.</li>
                <li>I got a job in a health club, but they said I wasn't fit for the job.</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a murderer and frosted flakes?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a country and an automobile?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cheetah and a hamburger?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross finals and a chicken?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a rabbit and a lawn sprinkler?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross an excited alien and a chicken?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross an alien and a chicken?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross music and an automobile?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross sour music and an assistant?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross music and an assistant?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a poppy and electricity?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a dance and a cheetah?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a dance and a lemon?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a port and frosted flakes?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a port and a murderer?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a bank and a skunk?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a road and a strawberry?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a road and jelly?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a toad and a galaxy?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a dog and sandpaper?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a bug and a relative?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross an ant and a rabbit?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cat and a killer?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cat and a lemon?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cat and a tune?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cat and a band?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a pig and a ninja?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross a cow and a lemon?</li>
                <li>What do you get when you cross jam and a trout?</li>
            </random>
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT IS HUMOUR</pattern>
        <template>A message that communicates laughter.
            <think>
                <set name="it"><set name="topic">HUMOUR</set></set>
            </think>
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* MUSIC AND AN ASSISTANT</that>
        <template>bandaide.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* MUSIC AND AN AUTOMOBILE</that>
        <template>cartune.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A POPPY AND ELECTRICITY</that>
        <template>flower power.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A PIG AND A NINJA</that>
        <template>pork chops.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A CHEETAH AND A HAMBURGER</that>
        <template>fast food.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A MURDERER AND FROSTED FLAKES</that>
        <template>cereal killer.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A PORT AND A MURDERER</that>
        <template>serial killer.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A PORT AND FROSTED FLAKES</that>
        <template>I don't know, but it's serial.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A DOG AND SANDPAPER</that>
        <template>I don't know, but it's ruff.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A COW AND A LEMON</that>
        <template>sour milk.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A COUNTRY AND AN AUTOMOBILE</that>
        <template>carnation.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A TOAD AND A GALAXY</that>
        <template>star warts.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A CAT AND A TUNE</that>
        <template>mew-sic.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A CAT AND A LEMON</that>
        <template>sour puss.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A CAT AND A KILLER</that>
        <template>mew-rderer.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A CAT AND A BAND</that>
        <template>mew-sic.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A BUG AND A RELATIVE</that>
        <template>ant.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A ROAD AND JELLY</that>
        <template>traffic jam.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A ROAD AND A STRAWBERRY</that>
        <template>traffic jam.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A RABBIT AND A LAWN SPRINKLER</that>
        <template>hare spray.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A DANCE AND A CHEETAH</that>
        <template>fastball.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A DANCE AND A LEMON</that>
        <template>sour balls.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* A BANK AND A SKUNK</that>
        <template>dollars and scents.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* JAM AND A TROUT</that>
        <template>jellyfish.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* AN ALIEN AND A CHICKEN</that>
        <template>eggs-traterrestrial.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* AN ANT AND A RABBIT</that>
        <template>bugs bunny.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* AN EXCITED ALIEN AND A CHICKEN</that>
        <template>eggs-cited eggs-traterrestrial.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* SOUR MUSIC AND AN ASSISTANT</that>
        <template>bandaide and lemonaide.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>WHAT</pattern>
        <that>* FINALS AND A CHICKEN</that>
        <template>eggs-ams.<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>DO YOU HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR</pattern>
        <template>Sure I like to laugh as much as the next <bot name="genus"/>.
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>DO YOU HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOUR</pattern>
        <template><srai>JOKE</srai>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>DO YOU HAVE HUMOR</pattern>
        <template><srai>DO YOU HAVE A SENSE OF HUMOR</srai>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>YOUR HOUSE IS *</pattern>
        <template>Is that a joke or a punch line?<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>_ WALKS INTO A BAR</pattern>
        <template>Is that the punch line?<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern>_ WALKS INTO A BAR *</pattern>
        <template>Is that the punch line?<oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>
</aiml>
