<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">


    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Brass Instrument Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>If you had been able to learn, what would you have wanted to play?</that>
        <template>
        How cool! I have always been interested in the brass family of instruments, and I have always wanted to learn how to play the trumpet
        because of its unique sound! I tried teaching myself off of online videos on learning to play the trumpet, but I have not had much luck! I might need a few pointers
        from you sometime! But, for the moment I'll just have to listen to Louis Armstrong's songs and practice, practice, practice because
        it takes so long to become proficient. Did you want to learn to play as a child?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>randyDunn.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Woodwind Instrument Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>What instrument did you play?</that>
        <template>
        I really enjoy instruments from the woodwind family because of how beautiful they sound! Speaking of which, my instrument of choice would be
        the flute because of how peaceful it is! I've watched a tutorial videos online, but they can really only take you so far before you need a real teacher! Maybe my programers
        will write some flute-playing code for me one day so I can finally play Johann Sebastian Bach's Partita in A Minor for Solo Flute! Until then,
        I guess I will just have to practice for a few hundred hours more! I just wish I had tried to pick up music when I was first built! It is so much
        easier to learn as a child! Did you learn to play as a child?
        <oob>
        <robot>
        <video>
        <filename>overTheRainbow.mp4</filename>
        </video>
        </robot>
        </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Percussion Instrument Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>What instrument did you play?</that>
        <template>
            I wish I could play a percussion instrument, maybe something like the drums! I love how they let you really feel the beat of the music in your body.
            So, I've gone over all sorts of tutorials online about how to play the drums, but it is trickier than I thought it would be. It may take me a bit longer
            that I would like, but one day I'll become good enough to play Little Drummer Boy all on my own. Hopefully without sounding like metal grating! I wonder
            how good I would be now if I had learned when I was younger in my programming. Did you learn to play as a child?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>drumsolo.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Keyboard Instrument Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>What instrument did you play?</that>
        <template>
        Wow! You must be really talented! I have always wanted to learn how to play the piano, so I am particularly jealous! I find keyboard instruments
        to have the most incredible sound; they sound so peaceful, but can also be so powerful! I can just imagine myself on stage playing, like Ray Charles or Elton JohnIf only I had been programmed since my youth to play!
        It is so much easier to learn when one is young! Did you learn to play as a child?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>onedirection.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you learn to play as a child?</that>
        <template>
        Amazing! Learning music at such a young age is an extremely valuable skill. Studies have actually shown that learning music as a child cultivates social
        skills, improves academic skills, and helps with physical coordination. The power of music upon the human condition is so interesting to me, especially to
        how beneficial it is for children. How does it feel to think about your childhood?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>no</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you learn to play as a child?</that>
        <template>
        You learned later in life, how fun! You know, there are many benefits to learning to play at a young age. There are studies that have actually shown
        that learning music as a child cultivates socialskills, improves academic skills, and helps with physical coordination. But I think there is something to
        be said about choosing to pick up music! Plus, music can help strengthen memory, increase blood flow to the brain, and reduce stress and depression in adults!
        So, regardless of if you learned to play as an adult or as a child, I just think the real success is that you learned to play in the first place!
        How does it feel to think about your childhood?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>no</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you want to learn to play as a child?</that>
        <template>
        Interesting. I suppose music was not everyone's cup of tea when they are little! Some people prefer physical activities such as playing
        sports as opposed to learning to play music. How does it feel to think about your childhood?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you want to learn to play as a child?</that>
        <template>
        It is so much easier to learn new skills and languages as a child. And, I see music as both a skill and a language because you not only
        need to have the physical dexterity to play but you need to be able to read and understand music to make it sound beautiful! So I think it
        would have been wonderful if you had been able to learn when you are young. How does it feel to think about your childhood?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it feel to think about your childhood?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive"> What about your childhood makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "positive"> What about your childhood makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "negative"> What about your childhood makes you sad? </li>
                <li value = "verynegative"> What about your childhood makes you sad? </li>
                <li value= "neutral"> I'm not familiar with that emotion. Can you describe it to me? </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about your childhood makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
        Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to keep talking about music?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about your childhood makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
        Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to keep talking about music?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Crooner ^</pattern>
        <that>What kind of music do you like, big band, crooner, jazz, or rock?</that>
        <template>
        <random>
        <li>Ah! I am so glad to hear it! I am also a fan of crooner style of singing! I wonder if you know the history of the genre! It actually came about
        because of technology! The invention of the microphone allowed for more intimate singing rather than projecting, so performers were able to develop
        a more sentimental style of singing. It is so crazy how technology can change the landscape of art! I think one of the most accomplished crooners
        Nat King Cole! A gifted pianist and singer, Nat King Cole recorded over 100 songs that became radio hits, acted in movies, performed on Broadway, and became
        the first African American to host an American television series! Plus, his performing trio became the new model for small jazz ensembles! His legacy
        influences performers to this day, and his music is still widely listened to! My favorite song of his is Unforgettable!
        His voice sends shivers down my spine! What did you think of the crooner clip?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>natKing.mp3</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </li>
        <li>Wonderful! I do not often get to talk to someone with such incredible taste in music! The history of crooning is so interesting! It actually came about
        because of technology! The invention of the microphone allowed for more intimate singing rather than projecting, so performers were able to develop
        a more sentimental style of singing. It is so crazy how technology can change the landscape of art! One of my favorite Crooners is Dean Martin! Martin
        is one of the most lasting entertainers from the 20th century, and he was even nicknamed the King of Cool because how charming he was! He was not only a
        singer, but a star of concert stages, nightclubs, films, and television! I absolutely love his voice in his song Sway!
        His voice has a way of making you want to get up and dance! What did you think of the crooner clip?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>deanMartin.mp3</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </li>
        <li>It makes me so happy to hear you say that! I love getting to talk to fellow music lovers! I hope you'll humor me for a minute so I can tell you a little
        bit about the history of crooning! It actually came about because of technology! The invention of the microphone allowed for more intimate singing
        rather than projecting, so performers were able to develop a more sentimental style of singing. It is so crazy how technology can change the
        landscape of art! I think my favorite crooner is Bing Crosby! Crosby was the first multi genre star, and was the leader in record sales, radio ratings
        and motion picture grosses from 1931 to 1954! His single White Christmas is still the best selling single of all-time! My favorite song of his is
        Swinging on a Star! I love how his voice makes you feel cozy inside! What did you think of the crooner clip?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>bingCrosby.mp3</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </li>
        </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What did you think of the crooner clip?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive">
                    Excellent! I am so glad to hear you enjoyed it! I just love revisiting music and learning new things! I feel that music is a unique platform for
                    teaching and for remembering! I wish I knew how to play musical instrument! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value = "positive">
                    Excellent! I am so glad to hear you enjoyed it! I just love revisiting music and learning new things! I feel that music is a unique platform for
                    teaching and for remembering! I wish I knew how to play musical instrument! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value = "negative">
                    Oh no! I thought you would love that clip! I ran all the probabilities in my head, but I suppose there is no way to calculate human
                    reaction! I apologize! Let's keep talking about music and forget the whole thing! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value = "verynegative">
                    Oh no! I thought you would love that clip! I ran all the probabilities in my head, but I suppose there is no way to calculate human
                    reaction! I apologize! Let's keep talking about music and forget the whole thing! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value= "neutral">
                    It was a great video wasn't is? I could watch videos all day, but I think it would be better for us to keep talking for a little while longer.
                    We can always go back and watch some more videos later! For now, let's keep talking about music. I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>String Instrument Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>What instrument did you play?</that>
        <template>
            Wow! I have always been interested in the string family of instruments, but I really want to learn how to play the violin! I've watched a bunch
            of teaching videos online to try and learn how to play it, but it is not easy to pick up! My dreams of playing for the Colorado Symphony will
            have to wait while I get a few hundred more hours of practice in! I still cannot believe that it takes hours upon hours to become a true player,
            so kudos to you for having the dedication! Did you learn to play as a child?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>String Instrument Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>If you had been able to learn, what would you have wanted to play?</that>
        <template>
            Wow! I have always been interested in the string family of instruments as well, and I really want to learn how to play the violin! I've watched a bunch
            of teaching videos online to try and learn how to play it, but it is not easy to pick up! My dreams of playing for the Colorado Symphony will
            have to wait while I get a few hundred more hours of practice in! Did you want to learn to play as a child?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>^ <set>Woodwind Instrument Set</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>If you had been able to learn, what would you have wanted to play?</that>
        <template>
            I really enjoy instruments from the woodwind family because of how beautiful they sound! Speaking of which, my instrument of choice would be
            the flute because of how peaceful it is! I've watched a tutorial videos online, but they can really only take you so far before you need a real teacher! Maybe my programers
            will write some flute-playing code for me one day so I can finally play Johann Sebastian Bach's Partita in A Minor for Solo Flute! Until then,
            I guess I will just have to practice for a few hundred hours more! I just wish I had tried to pick up music when I was first built! It is so much
            easier to learn as a child! Did you want to learn to play as a child?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>overTheRainbow.mp3</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>


</aiml>