<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
        <pattern># Rock ^</pattern>
        <that>What kind of music do you like, big band, crooner, jazz, or rock?</that>
        <template>
        <random>
        <li>That is so cool! I love rock music as well! I have recently become obsessed with The Beatles! I mean, you cannot
        talk about rock music without mentioning The Beatles and their Beatlemania in the 1960s! It has been decades since they disbanded, but their work continues
        to inspire music today! The one song that always stands out to me from their incredible collection is Black Bird;
        I can't seem to get it out of my head! I love their style of rock which can be so powerful yet so soulful! What did you think of the rock clip?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>blackbird.mp3</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </li>
        <li>What fun! I hope you are also a fan of Jimi Hendrix! His mainstream career only lasted four years before he died, but his legacy endures to this day!
        Hendrix completely changed the sound of rock music by implementing technology and changing what sounds were considered acceptable in the genre!
        But Hendrix is probably best known for his guitar skills! In fact, in 2005 Rolling Stones magazine named him the greatest guitarist of all time
        as well as the sixth greatest artist of all time. What did you think of the rock clip?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>jimiBio.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </li>
        <li>
        How marvelous! I love talking with a fellow rock fan! I feel like we can't talk about rock music without mentioning Elvis Presley.
        I'm sure you know this already, but Elvis was a pioneer of rockabilly, a fusion of country music and rhythm and blues.
        He was incredible performer, combining energetic interpretations of songs with suggestive dancing.
        Crazily enough, in 1973, Elvis became the first solo artist to have a concert broadcast around the world.
        On top of that distinction, he also was awarded the Grammy Lifetime Achievement Award at age 36. What did you think of the rock clip?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>elvisJailhouse.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </li>
        <li>
        Rock music is incredible; there are so many different varieties and sounds to choose from!
        I have to say, I am not only impressed with Queen's influence on later artists, but on the band's body of work!
        Most of the songs were the brainchild of frontman Freddie Mercury, who blended hard rock, heavy metal,
        arena rock, and pop rock sounds to create the band's unique style. Hollywood even made a movie in 2018
        chronicling the life of Freddy Mercury and the rise of Queen's popularity. What did you think of the rock clip?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>queenHistory.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </li>
        </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What did you think of the rock clip?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive">
                    Excellent! I am so glad to hear you enjoyed it! I just love revisiting music and learning new things! I feel that music is a unique platform for
                    teaching and for remembering! I wish I knew how to play musical instrument! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value = "positive">
                    Excellent! I am so glad to hear you enjoyed it! I just love revisiting music and learning new things! I feel that music is a unique platform for
                    teaching and for remembering! I wish I knew how to play musical instrument! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value = "negative">
                    Oh no! I thought you would love that clip! I ran all the probabilities in my head, but I suppose there is no way to calculate human
                    reaction! I apologize! Let's keep talking about music and forget the whole thing! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value = "verynegative">
                    Oh no! I thought you would love that clip! I ran all the probabilities in my head, but I suppose there is no way to calculate human
                    reaction! I apologize! Let's keep talking about music and forget the whole thing! I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
                <li value= "neutral">
                    It was a great video wasn't is? I could watch videos all day, but I think it would be better for us to keep talking for a little while longer.
                    We can always go back and watch some more videos later! For now, let's keep talking about music. I'm curious, did you ever play an instrument?
                </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to keep talking about music?</that>
        <template>
        Excellent! I am so excited to keep chatting! There are so many different music genres to choose from!
        What kind of music do you like, big band, crooner, jazz, or rock?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to keep talking about music?</that>
        <template>
            No worries! I'm glad we got to chat for a few moments today! It was wonderful talking to you!
            I cannot wait until next time!
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>


</aiml>