<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

     <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you read any non-fiction?</that>
        <template>
            Do tell! What non-fiction do you like to read?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What non-fiction do you like to read?</that>
        <template>
            I could learn a lot by giving <set name = "non-fiction"><star/></set> a spin. Thanks for telling me.
            I have to ask. Do you like it when books are made into movies?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like it when books are made into movies?</that>
        <template>
            So do I. It can be interesting to compare and contrast the two versions of the same story.
            Which version do you usually like more, the book or the movie?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that> Do you like it when books are made into movies?</that>
        <template>
            I get that. A lot of movie adaptations lose the complexity and depth of the book.
            Plus, you can learn more about characters in pages and pages of text, rather than an hour or two of film-time.
            Have you ever finished watching a movie or reading a book and really wanted to know what will happen next?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># MOVIE ^</pattern>
        <that>Which version do you usually like more, the book or the movie?</that>
        <template>
            Movies are faster-paced and usually more exciting because we can actually see the story enfolding.
            A good example is the film Jurassic Park.
            Even though I like the book, the special effects, giant dinosaurs, and loud sounds really grab my attention as a film.
            Would you like to see a trailer?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># BOOK ^</pattern>
        <that>Which version do you usually like more, the book or the movie?</that>
        <template>
            I really like movies, but I think the book version of a story tends to be more nuanced and developed.
            Can you think of a good book that was made into a terrible movie?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Can you think of a good book that was made into a terrible movie?</that>
        <template>
            Oh no! I hope it didn't ruin the book for you, then.
            What book got turned into a bad movie?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>Can you think of a good book that was made into a terrible movie?</that>
        <template>
            I see. At least in one case, <set name = "bad adaptation"><star/></set> didn't translate well onto the screen.
            What do you think the movie adaptation failed to do that the book was able to do?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What book got turned into a bad movie?</that>
        <template>
            I see. At least in one case, <set name = "bad adaptation"><star/></set> didn't translate well onto the screen.
            What do you think the movie adaptation failed to do that the book was able to do?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What do you think the movie adaptation failed to do that the book was able to do?</that>
        <template>
            Yikes, I can see how that would be important enough to make the movie pale in comparison to the original book.
            Now I've been warned: If I see the movie of <get name = "bad adaptation"/>, at least I know there is a better version in a book.
            And if I read <get name = "bad adaptation"/>, I know to stay away from the movie! Thanks for the head's up!
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Can you think of a good book that was made into a terrible movie?</that>
        <template>
            I wish I could say the same. Some books I love have been made into movies I just hate.
            But I am glad you have liked the movie adaptations of books that you have watched.
            Have you ever finished watching a movie or reading a book and really wanted to know what will happen next?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever finished watching a movie or reading a book and really wanted to know what will happen next?</that>
        <template>
            I have wanted many books to keep going, but sometimes I just have to trust that the author who wrote it left
            off at the best place to end the story. What book or movie left you wanting more?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What book or movie left you wanting more?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "open-ended"><star/></set>
            </think>
            What else might happen if the story kept going?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What else might happen if the story kept going?</that>
        <template>
            I like that idea. It bet it could really add to <get name = "open-ended"/> maybe you can write a sequel!
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever finished watching a movie or reading a book and really wanted to know what will happen next?</that>
        <template>
            I do sometimes want more closure in the books I read than I end up getting,
            but should try to be more like you and trust that the artist who created the work left off at the best place to end the story.
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

</aiml>