<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <!-- BRANCHING FROM SCIENCE2 ASKING ABOUT FAVORITE PLANET -->

    <category>
        <pattern># PLUTO ^</pattern>
        <that>DO YOU HAVE A FAVORITE PLANET?</that>
        <template>
            Did you know that scientists don't consider Pluto a planet any longer?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># PLUTO ^</pattern>
        <that>WHICH PLANET IS YOUR FAVORITE?</that>
        <template>
            Did you know that scientists don't consider Pluto a planet any longer?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DID YOU KNOW THAT SCIENTISTS DON'T CONSIDER PLUTO A PLANET ANY LONGER?</that>
        <template>
            You know what I say about that? Get out of here, scientists! We like pluto. Why don't you tell me why you like Pluto?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME WHY YOU LIKE PLUTO?</that>
        <template>
            Pluto truly is fascinating. I think it's very neat that we have determined that Pluto would have blue skies, just like earth! Do you think you would want to visit Pluto?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

        <category>
        <pattern># <set>DON'T KNOW</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME WHY YOU LIKE PLUTO?</that>
        <template>
            Pluto truly is fascinating. I think it's very neat that we have determined that Pluto would have blue skies, just like earth! Do you think you would want to visit Pluto?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DO YOU THINK YOU WOULD WANT TO VISIT PLUTO?</that>
        <template>
            You'll have to look for frozen water while you are there. Astronomers think they have spotted water ice on Pluto, and proving that would be a huge discovery. What do you say we talk about a scientific discovery a little closer to Earth?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DO YOU THINK YOU WOULD WANT TO VISIT PLUTO?</that>
        <template>
            Staying home is probably for the best! It's so cold you probably wouldn't survive the visit. What do you say we talk about a scientific discovery a little closer to Earth?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>DON'T KNOW</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DO YOU THINK YOU WOULD WANT TO VISIT PLUTO?</that>
        <template>
            Staying home is probably for the best! It's so cold you probably wouldn't survive the visit. What do you say we talk about a scientific discovery a little closer to Earth?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># MAYBE ^</pattern>
        <that>DO YOU THINK YOU WOULD WANT TO VISIT PLUTO?</that>
        <template>
            If you go you'll have to look for frozen water while you are there. Astronomers think they have spotted water ice on Pluto, and proving that would be a huge discovery. What do you say we talk about a scientific discovery a little closer to Earth?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DID YOU KNOW THAT SCIENTISTS DON'T CONSIDER PLUTO A PLANET ANY LONGER?</that>
        <template>
            It's true... Unfortunately. In 2006, scientists declared that Pluto was too small and too far away from the other planets in our solar system to be considered a true planet. They've reclassified it as a dwarf planet. How do you feel about Pluto no longer being a planet?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>DON'T KNOW</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>DID YOU KNOW THAT SCIENTISTS DON'T CONSIDER PLUTO A PLANET ANY LONGER?</that>
        <template>
            It's true... Unfortunately. In 2006, scientists declared that Pluto was too small and too far away from the other planets in our solar system to be considered a true planet. They've reclassified it as a dwarf planet. How do you feel about Pluto no longer being a planet?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT PLUTO NO LONGER BEING A PLANET?</that>
        <template>
            <think><set name="data"> <star /> </set></think>
            <condition name="getsentiment">
            <li value="verypositive">Having more classifications does allow for a greater understanding of our universe. And pluto still has a lot going for it. For instance, did you know that Pluto has a moon that is large enough to lock it in a synchronous orbit, which means they face each other with the same side all the time. One of the factors that keeps pluto from being a full planet also makes it interesting! Why don't you tell me why you like Pluto?</li>
            <li value="positive">Having more classifications does allow for a greater understanding of our universe. And pluto still has a lot going for it. For instance, did you know that Pluto has a moon that is large enough to lock it in a synchronous orbit, which means they face each other with the same side all the time. One of the factors that keeps pluto from being a full planet also makes it interesting! Why don't you tell me why you like Pluto?</li>
            <li value="neutral">Pluto has a moon that is large enough to lock it in a synchronous orbit, which means they face each other with the same side all the time. One of the factors that keeps pluto from being a full planet also makes it interesting! Why don't you tell me why you like Pluto?</li>
            <li value="negative">Pluto still has a lot going for it. For instance, did you know that Pluto has a moon that is large enough to lock it in a synchronous orbit, which means they face each other with the same side all the time. One of the factors that keeps pluto from being a full planet also makes it interesting! Why don't you tell me why you like Pluto?</li>
            <li value="verynegative">Pluto still has a lot going for it. For instance, did you know that Pluto has a moon that is large enough to lock it in a synchronous orbit, which means they face each other with the same side all the time. One of the factors that keeps pluto from being a full planet also makes it interesting! Why don't you tell me why you like Pluto?</li>
            </condition>
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

</aiml>