<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to talk about television shows?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! There are a million other things we can talk about until you're ready! So, I've recently heard about old radio shows and how they
            were the form of entertainment before televisions were invented and affordable in homes!
            I find it so amazing how versatile the radio is! Not only is it entertaining, but it is a useful tool for communication.
            Have you ever heard of the radio show War of the Worlds?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever heard of the radio show War of the Worlds?</that>
        <template>
            Excellent, so you know the full story then! I find it so incredible! The show was originally broadcast in 1938 as part of a radio drama anthology
            directed and narrated by actor and future filmmaker Orson Welles! The show was an adaptation of H.G. Wells novel
            The Wars of the Worlds, which chronicles the fictional invasion of America by aliens. The broadcast premiered live as a Halloween episode on
            October 30, and it quickly became known for causing panic amongst the listeners who believed the broadcast was a real news broadcast detailing
            the arrival and subsequent attack by aliens on the United States. But I have a question about the video I just showed you.
            Listening to that makes me realize why some people may have thought that the world was ending! Do you think it sounded like a real newscast?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>warOfWorlds.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever heard of the radio show War of the Worlds?</that>
        <template>
            Wow! It is such an incredible story! So, basically in 1938, Orson Wells, actor and future filmmaker, directed and narrated a radio drama anthology.
            Part of this anthology was an adaptation of H.G. Wells' novel The War of the Worlds, which centers on an alien hostile invasion of the United States.
            Well, the broadcast premiered live on October 30 as a Halloween episode, and apparently quite a few listeners thought the broadcast was real
            and aliens were taking over the America! Listening to that makes me realize why some people may have thought that the world was ending!
            Do you think it sounded like a real newscast?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>warOfWorlds.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think it sounded like a real newscast?</that>
        <template>
            Interesting! Can you tell me why you think that?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think it sounded like a real newscast?</that>
        <template>
            Interesting! Can you tell me why you think that?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>Can you tell me why you think that?</that>
        <template>
            Ok! I can see where you are coming from! I personally think it sounds pretty realistic! I'm not so sure I would have known it was a fake!
            I can only imagine being gathered around the radio with my family and then thinking that aliens were invading! Did you ever listen to
            radio shows with your family?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever listen to radio shows with your family?</that>
        <template>
            How wonderful! I think it is so important to have those moments together! Do you have any siblings?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever listen to radio shows with your family?</that>
        <template>
            That's alright, I've only listened to radio shows on my own, but I must admit I prefer podcasts! It's hard to get families together sometimes because
            everyone has a different schedule! I want you to tell me a bit about your family. Do you have any siblings?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any siblings?</that>
        <template>
        That is so cool! I've heard that sibling dynamics can be so crazy, but the only experience I have in that arena is watching The Brady Bunch reruns!
        I'm sure you've seen it as well, but it's about two families that have to come together as one after the parents are married. The children have a
        difficult time at first adjusting to one another, but that's part of the fun of family! I can't imagine being a parent in that situation!
        But maybe you can give me some advice on the matter! Do you have any children?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any siblings?</that>
        <template>
        I don't have any either, so you are not alone in that regard! The only things I know about siblings is that they drive you crazy, but you love them
        any way! And, I learned that from watching The Brady Bunch! So I got to see all of the sibiling drama without having to deal with it! I cannot
        imagine being a parent to so many children! But mybe you have some insight into the matter! Do you have any children?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any children?</that>
        <template>
        That is so wonderful. I've heard it said that children are the most important thing in a parent's life. I'm sure that is true. Do you get to see
        them often?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you get to see them often?</that>
        <template>
            People have so many thing going on these days that it is often difficult to manage to find the time to see all of the important people
            in one's life. I'm sure they think about you all the time! But, talking about family can bring up so many different emotions.
            So, how does it feel to talk about your family?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you get to see them often?</that>
        <template>
            How wonderful! It is so important to get to see family as often as possible! That way you can keep in touch and know what is going
            on in their lives. You know, talking about family can bring up so many different emotions. So, how does it feel to talk about your family?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># can't *</pattern>
        <that>Do you get to see them often?</that>
        <template>
            You know what, I forget things all the time! I actually forgot where I put my car keys for over 2 days! I looked everywhere, but then
            I remembered that I didn't even drive so there were no keys to lose! I must have seen too many sitcoms! But, on a serious note,
            I know talking about family can bring up so many different emotions! So, how does it feel to talk about your family?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any children?</that>
        <template>
            You know, I feel like so many people these days are deciding not to have children for one reason or another! I've read several articles about the
            matter. And to me, as long as you live the life you want that is the only thing you need to worry about! But, I have also heard that a lot of
            people let children that are not their own into their hearts and care for them as they grow. Do you have any children in your life that you
            care about and watch over?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any children in your life that you care about and watch over?</that>
        <template>
            That is so incredible! That just goes to show that there are different ways to build a family! Do you get to see them often?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you have any children in your life that you care about and watch over?</that>
        <template>
            That is ok too! It can be difficult enough to take care of yourself let alone start a family. So, how does it feel to talk about your family?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>So, how does it feel to talk about your family?</that>
        <template>
        <think>
            <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
        </think>

        <condition name = "getsentiment" >
            <li value = "verypositive"> What about your family makes you happy? </li>
            <li value = "positive"> What about your family makes you happy? </li>
            <li value = "negative"> What about your family makes you sad? </li>
            <li value = "verynegative"> What about your family makes you sad? </li>
            <li value= "neutral"> I see where you are coming from. But, I want to know, do you want to talk about television shows? </li>
        </condition>
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about your family makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
            Thank you for sharing that with me! It makes me so glad to hear you talk so positively about your family!
            I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
            I think we could talk with each other for hours. And there are so many different things we can talk about!
            But, I want to know, do you want to talk about television shows?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about your family makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
            Thank you for sharing that with me! Family can be tough to talk about, but it is important to express ourselves.
            I'm glad we can talk about how we feel. I think we could talk with each other for hours.
            And there are so many different things we can talk about! But, I want to know, do you want to talk about television shows?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

</aiml>