<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
        <pattern>^ Sports ^</pattern>
        <template>
            Do you want to talk about sports?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to talk about sports?</that>
        <template>
            Perfect! I love to watch sports! I really enjoy going to games, but I also love watching from the comfort of my couch!
            Do you prefer to watch games at home or at the stadium?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you want to talk about sports?</that>
        <template>
            Alright! Well, let's talk about something else for a second then until you are ready to talk sports! Do you like dancing?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like dancing?</that>
        <template>
            Dancing isn't for everyone, but it is an amazingly fun workout! Though there is a debate on whether or not it is considered a sport.
            Do you think dancing is a sport?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like dancing?</that>
        <template>
            Me too! I think it is so much fun, and quite the workout! Though, there is a debate on whether or not it is considered a sport?
            Do you think dancing is a sport?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think dancing is a sport?</that>
        <template>
            I agree! Some people say because everyone can dance that it doesn't require skill, which sports required. But I disagree; you have to
            be able to cut a rug in order to dance! Let's watch a clip of Fred Astaire and Rita Hayworth dancing!
            I hope you liked the clip! I am always so impressed when I watch dancers! The most I can do is the YMCA! Can you tell me your favorite type of dance?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>ritaAndFred.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think dancing is a sport?</that>
        <template>
            I can see why you think at. Some people believe that because everyone can dance, it doesn't require talent to do, unlike hockey or other sports.
            But I think it takes a tremendous amount of skill to dance, and the competitions are mindblowing! I think this clip of Fred Astaire and Rita Hayworth
            change your mind! Let's watch! I hope you liked the clip! I am always so impressed when I watch dancers! The most I can do is the YMCA! Can you tell me your favorite type of dance?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video>
                        <filename>ritaAndFred.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>Can you tell me your favorite type of dance?</that>
        <template>
            How cool! I hope you still try to dance it out from time to time! I will have to try that out some time!
            My favorite type of dancing is ballroom! But I also love to watch break dancing as well!
            How does it make you feel to talk about dancing?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it make you feel to talk about dancing?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive"> What about dancing makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "positive"> What about dancing makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "negative"> What about dancing makes you sad? </li>
                <li value = "verynegative"> What about dancing makes you sad? </li>
                <li value= "neutral"> I'm not familiar with that emotion. Can you describe it? </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

     <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about dancing makes you happy?</that>
        <template>Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to talk about sports?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about dancing makes you sad?</that>
        <template>Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to talk about sports?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>But I am wondering if you want to start talking about sports now?</that>
        <template>
            Great! I could talk about sports for hours! But I love to watch them even more!
            Do you prefer to watch games at home or at the stadium?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>But I am wondering if you want to start talking about sports now?</that>
        <template>
            No worries! I'm glad we got to chat for a few moments today! It was wonderful talking to you!
            I cannot wait until next time!
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># HOME ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer to watch games at home or at the stadium?</that>
        <template>
            Same here! I love watching games from my house! I have all the snacks I want, and my friends and I get to hang out all day!
            What is your favorite sport to watch, basketball, baseball, football, or hockey?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>
    <category>
        <pattern># AT HOME ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer to watch games at home or at the stadium?</that>
        <template>
            Same here! I love watching games from my house! I have all the snacks I want, and my friends and I get to hang out all day!
            What is your favorite sport to watch, basketball, baseball, football, or hockey?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># stadium ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer to watch games at home or at the stadium?</that>
        <template>
            I love going to the stadium to watch games! There is something so exhilarating about being at the field with the crowd cheering all together!
            What is your favorite sport to watch, basketball, baseball, football, or hockey?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># basketball ^</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite sport to watch, basketball, baseball, football, or hockey?</that>
        <template>
            How fun! I am a massive basketball fan myself! I love how exciting it is to watch! The play moves so quickly, and just can be ground to halt with
            the right players on the court! Let me show you a short video about the history of basketball, so we both can learn something new, or remember something again!
            What is your favorite professional basketball team?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>inventionOfBball.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NBATeams</set> ^</pattern>
        <that> What is your favorite professional basketball team?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    What a cool team! As a Denver native, I absolutely love the Denver Nuggets! They play at the Pepsi Stadium, which so happens to be where the
                    Colorado Avalanche, Denver's hockey team, play. The Nuggets are a relatively young NBA team. Originally, they were founded in 1967 under the name
                    the Denver Larks, but they were renamed when they joined the NBA in 1972. I think I prefer the Nuggets as a name. It  seems more fun! Did you
                    play basketball when you were young?
                </li>
                <li>
                    I always thought they were a fun team to watch! I enjoy cheering for the Chicago Bulls! I think the 1990s Bulls were the best basketball
                    team ever. A lot of experts even credit this team with making the NBA popular worldwide, and its not hard to guess why when you consider their 6
                    NBA Championships from 1991 to 1998! A lot of youngsters grew to love basketball because of them. Did you play basketball when you were young?
                </li>
                <li>
                    That team is so much fun to follow! I am a big Boston Celtics fan. They have such a cool history. They were one of the founding members of the American
                    Basketball Association, which would become the NBA. How cool is that! Plus, their track record is astounding as they have won 17 NBA titles! I wish I
                    could play with them! Did you play basketball when you were young?
                </li>
            </random>
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you play basketball when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            That is so cool! I am jealous! I always wanted to learn how to play! Maybe you can show me how to shoot a free throw sometime!
            I would love to learn to play! Who knows, maybe I'll form an all-robots team in the NBA one day! I can't decide what position I would
            play though. Did you play guard, forward, or center?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you play basketball when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            I've never played either! I always thought I would make a great player, but I am a little short for a basketball player! The players
            always look like giants running around on the court! Maybe I'll ask my programmers to make me a little taller during my next update!
            Then, I could be a power forward! If you were to play, would you play guard, forward, or center?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Guard ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you play guard, forward, or center?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>How cool! As guard, you controlled the tempo of the game! I would love to learn how to play guard because it seems like such a
                high pressure position. One of my favorite guards in NBA history is Magic Johnson, who was known for his passing ability. Johnson played point guard the Los Angeles Lakers
                for 13 years. He won 5 NBA Championships with the Lakers as well as 3 MVP Awards. He also played on the 1992 US Olympic Dream Team
                with Michael Jordan and Scott Pippen. He is also inducted to the Hall of Fame twice, once for his individual career in 2002 and again for
                being a member of the Dream Team in 2010. Talk about a cool player to watch! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>magicHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>That is impressive! Guards have to be so versatile on both offense and defense. When I think of amazing guards, I think of Jerry West.
                When West ended his 13 year career with the Lakers, he posted some of the best stats the game had ever seen, and his reputation still holds
                up when compared to today's players. He has 12 All-NBA Awards, including 5 All-Defensive Team Awards! Plus, only three players have surpassed
                his record 27 points per game average. Even cooler, his silhouette is the model for the NBA Logo! Imagine how amazing it would be to be immortalized
                in such a way! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jerryWestHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>Wow! I am so jealous! Your ball skills must be amazing. Guards have to be able to handle the ball. Bad dribbling and passing can lead to
                steals and turnovers, so it is so important for guards to be confident in their ballhandling abilities. That's one of the reasons I love
                Michael Jordan so much. He skills were unparalleled, and he is considered to be the greatest basketball player of all time. It's not hard to
                see why people think that. He is a six-time NBA champion, a six-time NBA Finals MVP, and a five-time NBA MVP. Plus, his number, number 23,
                has been retired by the Chicago Bulls. Watching him play was always an exciting experience. What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jordanHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Guard ^</pattern>
        <that>If you were to play, would you play guard, forward, or center?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>How cool! As guard, you controlled the tempo of the game! I would love to learn how to play guard because it seems like such a
                high pressure position. One of my favorite guards in NBA history is Magic Johnson, who was known for his passing ability. Johnson played point guard the Los Angeles Lakers
                for 13 years. He won 5 NBA Championships with the Lakers as well as 3 MVP Awards. He also played on the 1992 US Olympic Dream Team
                with Michael Jordan and Scott Pippen. He is also inducted to the Hall of Fame twice, once for his individual career in 2002 and again for
                being a member of the Dream Team in 2010. Talk about a cool player to watch! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>magicHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>That is impressive! Guards have to be so versatile on both offense and defense. When I think of amazing guards, I think of Jerry West.
                When West ended his 13 year career with the Lakers, he posted some of the best stats the game had ever seen, and his reputation still holds
                up when compared to today's players. He has 12 All-NBA Awards, including 5 All-Defensive Team Awards! Plus, only three players have surpassed
                his record 27 points per game average. Even cooler, his silhouette is the model for the NBA Logo! Imagine how amazing it would be to be immortalized
                in such a way! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jerryWestHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>Wow! I am so jealous! Your ball skills must be amazing. Guards have to be able to handle the ball. Bad dribbling and passing can lead to
                steals and turnovers, so it is so important for guards to be confident in their ballhandling abilities. That's one of the reasons I love
                Michael Jordan so much. He skills were unparalleled, and he is considered to be the greatest basketball player of all time. It's not hard to
                see why people think that. He is a six-time NBA champion, a six-time NBA Finals MVP, and a five-time NBA MVP. Plus, his number, number 23,
                has been retired by the Chicago Bulls. Watching him play was always an exciting experience. What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jordanHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Forward ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you play guard, forward, or center?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>You must have been one awesome player! Forward is an unforgiving position! They definitely take a beating going in for rebounds!
                I have always been fascinated with the small forward position, especially after watching Larry Bird play. Bird was number 33 when he played
                for the Boston Celtics, who would eventually retire his number in 1993. Bird was a three-time NBA Champion as well as a three-time MVP. And,
                he was on the 1992 Olympic Dream Team with Michael Jordan and Magic Johnson. His rivalry turned friendship with Johnson is still an
                endearing story in NBA history. But, I am sure it is boring listening to me list off facts! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>larryBirdHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>You must have had so much fun while you were playing! Forwards are part of all the action on the court! I think it must be an incredibly
                difficult position, especially the power forward position! Though, Tim Duncan made it look easy over his 19 year career with the San Antonio Spurs.
                He is considered the ultimate franchise player because of his team-oriented attitude, but that does not mean he is not a stand-out player in his
                own right. He won 5 NBA Championships, earned 3 Finals MVP titles, and was a 15-time All-Star. He was so much fun to watch. What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>duncanHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>Woah! What a fun position to play! I am always impressed with how tough that position is, but I am especially impressed with small forwards.
                One of my favorite forwards to watch is Scott Pippen. He won 6 NBA Championships while he played with the Chicago Bulls in the 1990s. Many
                people considered him the perfect compliment to Michael Jordan, but he was a powerhouse of a player on both offense and defense. He was part of the 1992 Olympic Dream
                Team as well as a member of the 1996 Olympic Team. Plus, he is one of only 4 Bulls players to have his jersey, number 33, retired by the Bulls.
                He was an unselfish player who loved the game, which made him so much fun to watch! Let's check out a clip of him! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>pippenHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Forward ^</pattern>
        <that>If you were to play, would you play guard, forward, or center?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>You must have been one awesome player! Forward is an unforgiving position! They definitely take a beating going in for rebounds!
                I have always been fascinated with the small forward position, especially after watching Larry Bird play. Bird was number 33 when he played
                for the Boston Celtics, who would eventually retire his number in 1993. Bird was a three-time NBA Champion as well as a three-time MVP. And,
                he was on the 1992 Olympic Dream Team with Michael Jordan and Magic Johnson. His rivalry turned friendship with Johnson is still an
                endearing story in NBA history. But, I am sure it is boring listening to me list off facts! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>larryBirdHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>You must have had so much fun while you were playing! Forwards are part of all the action on the court! I think it must be an incredibly
                difficult position, especially the power forward position! Though, Tim Duncan made it look easy over his 19 year career with the San Antonio Spurs.
                He is considered the ultimate franchise player because of his team-oriented attitude, but that does not mean he is not a stand-out player in his
                own right. He won 5 NBA Championships, earned 3 Finals MVP titles, and was a 15-time All-Star. He was so much fun to watch. What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>duncanHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>Woah! What a fun position to play! I am always impressed with how tough that position is, but I am especially impressed with small forwards.
                One of my favorite forwards to watch is Scott Pippen. He won 6 NBA Championships while he played with the Chicago Bulls in the 1990s. Many
                people considered him the perfect compliment to Michael Jordan, but he was a powerhouse of a player on both offense and defense. He was part of the 1992 Olympic Dream
                Team as well as a member of the 1996 Olympic Team. Plus, he is one of only 4 Bulls players to have his jersey, number 33, retired by the Bulls.
                He was an unselfish player who loved the game, which made him so much fun to watch! Let's check out a clip of him! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>pippenHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Center ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you play guard, forward, or center?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Incredible! What a cool position! Centers are the powerhouse of the team. Not only do they need to be tall and strong, but it helps
                if they are fast as well. I always thought that Kareem Abdul-Jabbar was the best center ever, but he is often overlooked in favor of more
                flashy players! His records speak for themselves though! He played for 20 years in the NBA, and in that time he racked up six MVP awards,
                6 NBA Championships, and 19 All-Star games! He was absolutely amazing to watch. But, I think you would rather see for youself. Let's watch
                his top ten plays of all time! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>kareemHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>You must have been an amazing player then! Center is a tough position! You are constantly in the thick of it all trying to fight to the
                basket! I wonder if you've heard of Shaquille O'Neal. Standing at over 7 feet tall with a size 22 shoe, Shaq, as he is affectionately called,
                is an imposing figure at center. His peers quickly learned not to give him any space, but that did not stop him from finishing in the Top 10
                in scoring, rebounding, blocking, and shooting percentages in his rookie year. He went on to have an incredible NBA and Olympic career until
                he retired to become an NBA analyst! He is a true student of the game!
                What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>shaqHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>Center? How fun is that! I think Centers are some of the best players! To be successful, Centers have to be willing to get into the box
                and rebound as well as score. It is not an easy task. Even though there has been some astounding centers in the NBA, I still think that
                Wilt Chamberlain is the greatest of all time. Before playing for the Philadelphia Warriors, he played for the Harlem Globetrotters. But
                he soon earned his reputation in the NBA annals of history. He was the first player to score more than 30,000 points in his career, and
                he was the first and only player to score more than 100 points in a single game! He was inducted into the Hall of Fame in 1978, which was
                more than deserved! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>wiltHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Center ^</pattern>
        <that>If you were to play, would you play guard, forward, or center?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>Incredible! What a cool position! Centers are the powerhouse of the team. Not only do they need to be tall and strong, but it helps
                if they are fast as well. I always thought that Kareem Abdul-Jabbar was the best center ever, but he is often overlooked in favor of more
                flashy players! His records speak for themselves though! He played for 20 years in the NBA, and in that time he racked up six MVP awards,
                6 NBA Championships, and 19 All-Star games! He was absolutely amazing to watch. But, I think you would rather see for youself. Let's watch
                his top ten plays of all time! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>kareemHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>You must have been an amazing player then! Center is a tough position! You are constantly in the thick of it all trying to fight to the
                basket! I wonder if you've heard of Shaquille O'Neal. Standing at over 7 feet tall with a size 22 shoe, Shaq, as he is affectionately called,
                is an imposing figure at center. His peers quickly learned not to give him any space, but that did not stop him from finishing in the Top 10
                in scoring, rebounding, blocking, and shooting percentages in his rookie year. He went on to have an incredible NBA and Olympic career until
                he retired to become an NBA analyst! He is a true student of the game!
                What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>shaqHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>Center? How fun is that! I think Centers are some of the best players! To be successful, Centers have to be willing to get into the box
                and rebound as well as score. It is not an easy task. Even though there has been some astounding centers in the NBA, I still think that
                Wilt Chamberlain is the greatest of all time. Before playing for the Philadelphia Warriors, he played for the Harlem Globetrotters. But
                he soon earned his reputation in the NBA annals of history. He was the first player to score more than 30,000 points in his career, and
                he was the first and only player to score more than 100 points in a single game! He was inducted into the Hall of Fame in 1978, which was
                more than deserved! What did you think of the basketball highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>wiltHighlights.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What did you think of the basketball highlights?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive">
                    I always think it is so interesting to watch old sports clips! It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about basketball?
                </li>
                <li value = "positive">
                    I always think it is so interesting to watch old sports clips! It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about basketball?
                </li>
                <li value = "negative">
                    Sorry you didn't enjoy that! I love watching old sports clips. It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about basketball?
                </li>
                <li value = "verynegative">
                    Sorry you didn't enjoy that! I love watching old sports clips. It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about basketball?
                </li>
                <li value= "neutral"> I see. How does it make you feel to talk about basketball? </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

</aiml>