<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">


    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it make you feel to talk about baseball?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive"> What about baseball makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "positive"> What about baseball makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "negative"> What about baseball makes you sad? </li>
                <li value = "verynegative"> What about baseball makes you sad? </li>
                <li value= "neutral"> That seems understandable. I'm enjoying talking to you. Do you want to talk about sports? </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about baseball makes you happy?</that>
        <template>Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to talk about sports?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about baseball makes you sad?</that>
        <template>Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to talk about sports?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Football ^</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite sport to watch, basketball, baseball, football, or hockey?</that>
        <template>
            I love football! I love to see players push the boundaries of performance of the human body! Plus, any sport that has epic tailgating parties
            is a win in my book! Who is your favorite professional football team?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>footballHistory.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NFLTeams</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Who is your favorite professional football team?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    What a cool team! I have always loved the Denver Broncos! Did you know that the first male cheerleader for the Broncos was actually
                    Robin Williams? He was filming a scene for his sitcom Mork and Mindy, and he came out onto the field to rally the crowd during a 1979
                    game against the New England Patriots! Football fans know how to have fun! Did you ever play football?</li>
                <li>
                    That's a fun team! I am a fan of the Green Bay Packers! Did you know that their team is the only professional team to be owned
                    by the fans? Talk about wild! At least you know the owners are dedicated to the team and the game! Did you ever play football?
                </li>
            </random>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever play football?</that>
        <template>
            I haven't played either! Unless you count flag football once or twice! There are so many ways to play now though! They have elementary school
            teams for younger players, and some schools even organize Powder Puffs games for junior and senior girls to battle it out in high school to
            raise funds for charity! The options are endless for more people to play than ever before!
            If you had had the opportunity to play, which position would you have played, offense, defense, or special teams?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever play football?</that>
        <template>
            That's awesome! I haven't played actual football; just a couple of games of flag football! It looks so physically tolling on the body.
            Players definitely take a beating! Did you play on offense, defense, or special teams?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Offense ^</pattern>
        <that>Did play on offense, defense, or special teams?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    Offense would be so much fun to play! There are so many different positions to choose from! But, I think I would want to
                    be a quarterback, like Peyton Manning! Manning still holds the record for touchdown passes at 539! Plus, he makes some really
                    funny commercials! He is unbelievable on and off the field! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>peytonManning.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    I think Offense is the most exciting place to play! There are endless ways to be creative! But, if I had to choose a position on Offense,
                    I would want to be a running back! My circuits get chills when I watch footage of Walter Payton, the Chicago Bears' running back in the 1980s.
                    Nicknamed Sweetness for his personality and graceful athleticism, Walter Payton also known as a capable blocker, pass receiver, and passer.
                    He was quite the utility player, and he only missed one game in 13 seasons! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>walterPayton.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Ahhh Offense all the way! Defense is important, but I feel like Offense is where you get to have the most fun! I feel like I would
                    make an excellent wide receiver! I want to be the next Jerry Rice, who is a legend. Did you know that he holds a 274 game receiving streak?
                    He literally caught at least one catch for 274 straight games. Unreal! Plus, he was still playing at age 40! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jerryRice.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Offense ^</pattern>
        <that>If you had had the opportunity to play, which position would you have played, offense, defense, or special teams?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    Offense would be so much fun to play! There are so many different positions to choose from! But, I think I would want to
                    be a quarterback, like Peyton Manning! Manning still holds the record for touchdown passes at 539! Plus, he makes some really
                    funny commercials! He is unbelievable on and off the field! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>peytonManning.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    I think Offense is the most exciting place to play! There are endless ways to be creative! But, if I had to choose a position on Offense,
                    I would want to be a running back! My circuits get chills when I watch footage of Walter Payton, the Chicago Bears' running back in the 1980s.
                    Nicknamed Sweetness for his personality and graceful athleticism, Walter Payton also known as a capable blocker, pass receiver, and passer.
                    He was quite the utility player, and he only missed one game in 13 seasons! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>walterPayton.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Ahhh Offense all the way! Defense is important, but I feel like Offense is where you get to have the most fun! I feel like I would
                    make an excellent wide receiver! I want to be the next Jerry Rice, who is a legend. Did you know that he holds a 274 game receiving streak?
                    He literally caught at least one catch for 274 straight games. Unreal! Plus, he was still playing at age 40! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jerryRice.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Defense ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you play on offense, defense, or special teams?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    I feel like defense does not get enough credit! It is such an important part of the game; it just doesn't have the same glamour of offense!
                    If I were a defender, I think I would want to be a linebacker, like Dick Butkus from the Chicago Bears. Butkus was actually selected by both the
                    Chicago Bears and the Denver Broncos during the draft, but he decided to sign with the Bears because he was from Chicago. He went on to be selected
                    for eight consecutive Pro-Bowls in his short career! He was known for stripping the ball during his tackles. What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>dickButkus.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Defense is an insanely tough group! Though, I have always been partial to playing defensive tackle ever since I saw some footage of Reggie White
                    from the Green Bay Packers! He was one tough cookie! His 1986 to 1988 seasons saw him getting 57 sacks in only 44 games! And, he helped the Packers win
                    a Superbowl! He was unstoppable! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>reggieWhite.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Defense such an important component of the game! You can have an amazing Offense, but your team won't be anything without a decent
                    defense! If I was a defender, I would want to play Safety! I have always dreamed of making the game saving interception for a return
                    touchdown since I saw some archival footage of Rod Woodson doing just that! Woodson played both Safety and Cornerback, a pretty unusual
                    feat! Plus, he had longetivity and ended up playing in the NFL for 17 seasons! And did I mention his 17 touchdown returns? Simply amazing.
                    What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>rodWoodson.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Defense ^</pattern>
        <that>If you had had the opportunity to play, which position would you have played, offense, defense, or special teams?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    I feel like defense does not get enough credit! It is such an important part of the game; it just doesn't have the same glamour of offense!
                    If I were a defender, I think I would want to be a linebacker, like Dick Butkus from the Chicago Bears. Butkus was actually selected by both the
                    Chicago Bears and the Denver Broncos during the draft, but he decided to sign with the Bears because he was from Chicago. He went on to be selected
                    for eight consecutive Pro-Bowls in his short career! He was known for stripping the ball during his tackles. But, we should watch a clip;
                    that's way more interesting then me spouting off facts! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>dickButkus.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Defense is an insanely tough group! Though, I have always been partial to playing defensive tackle ever since I saw some footage of Reggie White
                    from the Green Bay Packers! He was one tough cookie! His 1986 to 1988 seasons saw him getting 57 sacks in only 44 games! And, he helped the Packers win
                    a Superbowl! He was unstoppable! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>reggieWhite.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Defense such an important component of the game! You can have an amazing Offense, but your team won't be anything without a decent
                    defense! If I was a defender, I would want to play Safety! I have always dreamed of making the game saving interception for a return
                    touchdown since I saw some archival footage of Rod Woodson doing just that! Woodson played both Safety and Cornerback, a pretty unusual
                    feat! Plus, he had longevity and ended up playing in the NFL for 17 seasons! And did I mention his 17 touchdown returns? Simply amazing.
                    What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>rodWoodson.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Special Teams ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you play on offense, defense, or special teams?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    Special Teams are such cool players! I think they don't get the recognition they deserve! I mean, look at JOhn Carney! He was a place kicker
                    for a bunch of different teams from 1987 to 2010! Talk about longevity! When he retired, he had 2044 points! He may not have been the best player,
                    but there is no denying he loved the game and put points up on the board! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>johnCarney.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    I love Special Teams! I mean, these are the players who usually specialize outside of their normal position! I still the first tome I watched Devin Hester
                    return a kick for a touchdown! You know, he was originally drafted as a cornerback, but became a kick returner! He actually holds the record for most all-time
                    return touchdowns, and he is first person to ever return the opening kick of the Super Bowl for a touchdown! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>devinHester.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Special Teams ^</pattern>
        <that>If you had had the opportunity to play, which position would you have played, offense, defense, or special teams?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    Special Teams are such cool players! I think they don't get the recognition they deserve! I mean, look at JOhn Carney! He was a place kicker
                    for a bunch of different teams from 1987 to 2010! Talk about longevity! When he retired, he had 2044 points! He may not have been the best player,
                    but there is no denying he loved the game and put points up on the board! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>johnCarney.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    I love Special Teams! I mean, these are the players who usually specialize outside of their normal position! I still the first tome I watched Devin Hester
                    return a kick for a touchdown! You know, he was originally drafted as a cornerback, but became a kick returner! He actually holds the record for most all-time
                    return touchdowns, and he is first person to ever return the opening kick of the Super Bowl for a touchdown! What did you think of the football highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>devinHester.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What did you think of the football highlights?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive">
                    I always think it is so interesting to watch old sports clips! It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about football?
                </li>
                <li value = "positive">
                    I always think it is so interesting to watch old sports clips! It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about football?
                </li>
                <li value = "negative">
                    Sorry you didn't enjoy that! I love watching old sports clips. It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about football?
                </li>
                <li value = "verynegative">
                    Sorry you didn't enjoy that! I love watching old sports clips. It's like going back in time to another world! I can remember where I
                    was when I saw some small part of history being made, but more importantly I remember how I felt at that exact moment.
                    How does it make you feel to talk about football?
                </li>
                <li value= "neutral"> I see. How does it make you feel to talk about football? </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it make you feel to talk about football?</that>
        <template>
            <think>
                <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
            </think>

            <condition name = "getsentiment" >
                <li value = "verypositive"> What about football makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "positive"> What about football makes you happy? </li>
                <li value = "negative"> What about football makes you sad? </li>
                <li value = "verynegative"> What about football makes you sad? </li>
                <li value= "neutral"> That seems understandable. I'm enjoying talking to you. Do you want to talk about sports? </li>
            </condition>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about football makes you happy?</that>
        <template>Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to talk about sports?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about football makes you sad?</that>
        <template>Thank you for sharing that with me! I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
        I think we could talk with each other for hours. Do you want to talk about sports?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Hockey ^</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite sport to watch, basketball, baseball, football, or hockey?</that>
        <template>
            I love watching hockey. I find it to be so fast-paced! The players are so impressive! I would fall flat on my face if I tried to skate,
            let alone at that speed! I can barely keep track of the puck! Who is your favorite hockey team?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NHLTeams</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Who is your favorite hockey team?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    That's such a fun team! I am a fan of the Colorado Avalanche- it must be the Denver native in me!
                    Did you know they had the first major professional sports championship for a Denver team when they won the Stanley Cup in 1996?
                    I wish I had been built back then so I could have watched them sweep the Florida Panthers!
                    Or, that I could have tried out for the team and played with them! Did you ever play hockey when you were young?
                </li>
                <li>
                    That's such an incredible team! I myself love the Chicago Blackhawks!
                    Did you know they held the NHL's record for the longest championship drought from 1961 to 2010, when they finally won their fourth Stanley Cup!
                    I wish I could have been in Chicago for that celebration! Or, that I could have tried out for the team and played with them!
                    Did you ever play hockey when you were young?
                </li>
            </random>
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever play hockey when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            That's ok! I never played either! I wanted to, but I have two left-feet on the ice!
            What position would you want to play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>^ <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you ever play hockey when you were young?</that>
        <template>
            That is so exciting! I always wanted to play, but robots on ice makes for a better sitcom than reality!
            What position did you play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Forward ^</pattern>
        <that>What position did you play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    How cool! Forwards have to be such versatile players! Whether it's setting up your teammate with the assist, or hustling
                    back to defend a power play, forwards have to do it all! One of my all-time favorite forwards to watch footage
                    of is Wayne Gretzky. He has more assists than any players has actual goals! He is called the Great One, and is widely considered to be
                    the greatest player of all time! And, he is the only player to have his number, number 99, retired by the NHL.
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>wayneGretzky.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    That is so wonderful! You have to be an incredible skate to be a forward! I was always in awe of Bobby Hull when he was playing!
                    He was known for his lightning-fast slap shot that goalies found infuriating! Plus, he helped the Chicago Blackhawks win the Stanley
                    Cup on 1961! He was one fun player to watch! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>bobbyHull.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    What an exciting position to play! I don't think I could even get the puck to the net let alone hit it with so much force! One of the
                    most exciting forwards to watch was Gordie Howe! He was a tough-as-nails player! In his career, which lasted from 1946 to 1980, he received
                    over 500 stitches to his face alone! Plus, he created the unofficial stat called the "Gordie Howe Hat Trick," for when player records a
                    goal, an assist, and a fight in one game! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>gordieHowe.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Forward ^</pattern>
        <that>What position would you want to play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    How cool! Forwards have to be such versatile players! Whether it's setting up your teammate with the assist, or hustling
                    back to defend a power play, forwards have to do it all! One of my all-time favorite forwards to watch footage
                    of is Wayne Gretzky. He has more assists than any players has actual goals! He is called the Great One, and is widely considered to be
                    the greatest player of all time! And, he is the only player to have his number, number 99, retired by the NHL.
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>wayneGretzky.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    That is so wonderful! You have to be an incredible skate to be a forward! I was always in awe of Bobby Hull when he was playing!
                    He was known for his lightning-fast slap shot that goalies found infuriating! Plus, he helped the Chicago Blackhawks win the Stanley
                    Cup on 1961! He was one fun player to watch! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>bobbyHull.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    What an exciting position to play! I don't think I could even get the puck to the net let alone hit it with so much force! One of the
                    most exciting forwards to watch was Gordie Howe! He was a tough-as-nails player! In his career, which lasted from 1946 to 1980, he received
                    over 500 stitches to his face alone! Plus, he created the unofficial stat called the "Gordie Howe Hat Trick," for when player records a
                    goal, an assist, and a fight in one game! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>gordieHowe.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Defenseman ^</pattern>
        <that>What position did you play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    That is so cool! Defense is an incredibly difficult position! You have to be able to not only skate insanely well to keep your mark,
                    but you also need to be a decent attacking player to help in the offensive zone! My favorite defenseman is Duncan Keith on the Chicago
                    Blackhawks! He is known as a two-way player, so he is skilled in shutdown and offensive roles!
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>duncanKeith.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Defense is such an important position! Not only is it crucial to protecting the net, but defensemen are an important component of offense!
                    That was not always the case though! Bobby Orr from the Boston Bruins completely revolutionized the defensive position! Rather than merely clearing the puck from the net,
                    Orr kept possession and frequently crossed the blue line to participate in offensive plays! Orr proceeded to shatter defenseman scoring records, and
                    even became the highest scorer in the NHL for two seasons! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>bobbyOrr.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Wow! You must have been really good because Defense is such an intensive position! You have to be an incredible skater because you are expected to
                    help on offense as well as defend the goal! I am always impressed when I watch old footage of Tim Horton! He was a solid defenseman for a whopping 24 seasons!
                    He was known for his incredible strength and his calmness under pressure. While he was an amazing player, he was also a businessman, and his Canadian coffee chain
                    called Tim Horton's is still popular to this day! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>timHorton.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Defenseman ^</pattern>
        <that>What position would you want to play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    That is so cool! Defense is an incredibly difficult position! You have to be able to not only skate insanely well to keep your mark,
                    but you also need to be a decent attacking player to help in the offensive zone! My favorite defenseman is Duncan Keith on the Chicago
                    Blackhawks! He is known as a two-way player, so he is skilled in shutdown and offensive roles!
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>duncanKeith.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Defense is such an important position! Not only is it crucial to protecting the net, but defensemen are an important component of offense!
                    That was not always the case though! Bobby Orr from the Boston Bruins completely revolutionized the defensive position! Rather than merely clearing the puck from the net,
                    Orr kept possession and frequently crossed the blue line to participate in offensive plays! Orr proceeded to shatter defenseman scoring records, and
                    even became the highest scorer in the NHL for two seasons! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>bobbyOrr.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Wow! You must have been really good because Defense is such an intensive position! You have to be an incredible skater because you are expected to
                    help on offense as well as defend the goal! I am always impressed when I watch old footage of Tim Horton! He was a solid defenseman for a whopping 24 seasons!
                    He was known for his incredible strength and his calmness under pressure. While he was an amazing player, he was also a businessman, and his Canadian coffee chain
                    called Tim Horton's is still popular to this day! What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>timHorton.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Goalie ^</pattern>
        <that>What position did you play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    That is incredible! Goalie literally have so much pressure put on them! They are the last line of defense, so they require such quick
                    reflexes to stop the puck! I love watching Martin Brodeur highlights. He holds several records for career wins and stops!
                    And, he won three Stanley Cups in his professional career. One of the reasons I love Brodeur is his style of play. He was an agressive
                    goalie. So aggressive that he inspired a rule change limiting the space a goalie was allowed to cover! Talk about an impact to the sport!
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>brodeur.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    How cool! You had the most difficult job on the ice in my opinion! Goalies have to have crazy reflexes or else they can't hope to respond in
                    time for how quickly the puck is shot! But, I can't talk about goalies without mentioning Jim Craig from the US Olympic 1980 Miracle Team. The Soviet
                    team was considered not only the best in the world, but a lot of people thought they were invincible! But, when the scrappy US team made up of college
                    players went up against the militaristic USSR, Craig helped defeat the Soviet Union by stopping 36 out of 39 shots.
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jimCraig.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Wow! I am impressed! I don't think I could be a goalie! The puck moves too fast for me! It would be in the back of the net before I even
                    fired up a circuit. I think the greatest goalie of all-time is Patrick Roy. He is known for his absolute resolve to win. During the
                    1993 Stanley Cup playoffs, he helped the Canadians win a record 10 consecutive sudden-death overtime games! He won four Stanley Cup trophies and
                    several MVP awards! He was quite the player! But I am sure I don't need to tell you that! Let's watch a video I found about him together though, to be safe!
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>patrickRoy.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Goalie ^</pattern>
        <that>What position would you want to play, forward, defenseman, or goalie?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    That is incredible! Goalie literally have so much pressure put on them! They are the last line of defense, so they require such quick
                    reflexes to stop the puck! I love watching Martin Brodeur highlights. He holds several records for career wins and stops!
                    And, he won three Stanley Cups in his professional career. One of the reasons I love Brodeur is his style of play. He was an agressive
                    goalie. So aggressive that he inspired a rule change limiting the space a goalie was allowed to cover! Talk about an impact to the sport!
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>brodeur.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    How cool! You had the most difficult job on the ice in my opinion! Goalies have to have crazy reflexes or else they can't hope to respond in
                    time for how quickly the puck is shot! But, I can't talk about goalies without mentioning Jim Craig from the US Olympic 1980 Miracle Team. The Soviet
                    team was considered not only the best in the world, but a lot of people thought they were invincible! But, when the scrappy US team made up of college
                    players went up against the militaristic USSR, Craig helped defeat the Soviet Union by stopping 36 out of 39 shots.
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>jimCraig.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Wow! I am impressed! I don't think I could be a goalie! The puck moves too fast for me! It would be in the back of the net before I even
                    fired up a circuit. I think the greatest goalie of all-time is Patrick Roy. He is known for his absolute resolve to win. During the
                    1993 Stanley Cup playoffs, he helped the Canadians win a record 10 consecutive sudden-death overtime games! He won four Stanley Cup trophies and
                    several MVP awards! He was quite the player! But I am sure I don't need to tell you that! Let's watch a video I found about him together though, to be safe!
                    What did you think of the hockey highlights?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>patrickRoy.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

</aiml>