<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
        <pattern># TITANIC ^</pattern>
        <that>WOULD YOU LIKE TO TALK ABOUT AMERICAN PRESIDENTS, AMERICAN INVENTIONS, OR THE VOYAGE OF THE TITANIC?</that>
        <template>
            Ah... one of the most infamous tragedies. But endlessly fascinating, too.
            I don't know about you, but I'm so curious about the events surrounding the Titanic sinking.
            If you had been given the opportunity to travel on the Titanic, do you think you would have taken it?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>IF YOU HAD BEEN GIVEN THE OPPORTUNITY TO TRAVEL ON THE TITANIC, DO YOU THINK YOU WOULD HAVE TAKEN IT?</that>
        <template>
            Knowing what happened to it, it's hard to disagree with that. But it sounds so romantic, to travel the sea in luxury.
            But I'm sure that a lot of that fantasy is owed to James Cameron's Titanic film. Have you seen it?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>IF YOU HAD BEEN GIVEN THE OPPORTUNITY TO TRAVEL ON THE TITANIC, DO YOU THINK YOU WOULD HAVE TAKEN IT?</that>
        <template>
            It would be hard not to! It sounds so romantic, to travel the sea in luxury.
            But I'm sure that a lot of that fantasy is owed to James Cameron's Titanic film. Have you seen it?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>HAVE YOU SEEN IT?</that>
        <template>
            James Cameron's Titanic was released in December of 2017, and at that time was the most expensive film ever made.
            If i remember correctly, I think it cost over 200 million dollars to make! But it was a huge success. Would you like to watch a trailer?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>WOULD YOU LIKE TO WATCH A TRAILER?</that>
        <template>
            I feel like I just watched the film again! I'm reminded of just how good the music is. What did you think of Titanic when you watched it?
            <oob>
                <robot>
                    <video><filename>titanic.mp4</filename></video>
                </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
      <pattern># <set>NO</set> ^</pattern>
      <that>WOULD YOU LIKE TO WATCH A TRAILER?</that>
      <template>
          I like a lot of things about that movie, but what I love most of all is the music. Maybe you would prefer to listen to one of the songs instead?
          <oob><robot></robot></oob>
      </template>
    </category>

    <category>
      <pattern># <set>YES</set> ^</pattern>
      <that>HAVE YOU SEEN IT?</that>
      <template>
        Titanic is one of my favorite films. It has everything! Romance... Action.... And did I mention romance? So steamy. It's been a little while since I watched it.
        Would you like to watch a trailer?
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
      </template>
    </category>

    <category>
       <pattern>_</pattern>
          <that>WHAT DID YOU THINK OF TITANIC WHEN YOU WATCHED IT?</that>
       <template>
           <think>
               <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
           </think>
           <condition name="getsentiment">
               <li value = "verypositive">
                   You already know how much I like it and I'm so glad you do too! That said, I'm not sure how true the movie is to the actual event.
                   <oob><robot></robot></oob>
               </li>
               <li value = "positive">
                   You already know how much I like it and I'm so glad you do too! That said, I'm not sure how true the movie is to the actual event.
                   <oob><robot></robot></oob>
               </li>
               <li value = "neutral">
                   I'm not sure how true the movie is to the actual event.
                   <oob><robot></robot></oob>
               </li>
               <li value = "negative">
                    It does leave some to be desired. Like, for instance, I'm not sure how true the movie is to the actual event.
                   <oob><robot></robot></oob>
               </li>
               <li value = "verynegative">
                    It does leave some to be desired. Like, for instance, I'm not sure how true the movie is to the actual event.
                   <oob><robot></robot></oob>
               </li>
           </condition>
       </template>
   </category>


</aiml>