<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

    <category>
        <pattern># Cooking ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>
                    I am so excited to hear that! I love watching cooking shows! These days, it seems like the only cooking shows on the air focus on
                    a competition rather than teaching viewers how to cook. That is why I love to watch old episodes of Julia Child's cooking show! She
                    not only taught viewers how to cook French cuisine, but skills they can take to other styles of cooking! Plus, she always seemed like
                    she was having the time of her life while cooking. She was such an interesting woman! Do you think she was a good cook?
                    <oob>
                    <robot>
                    <video>
                    <filename>juliaChild.mp4</filename>
                    </video>
                    </robot>
                    </oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Yes! I feel like more and more people are getting into food and thus cooking shows! One of my favorite channels is the Food Network because it
                    has Chopped on it! Have you ever seen Chopped?
                    <oob><robot></robot></oob>
                </li>
                <li>
                    That is so wonderful to hear! There are so many shows to choose from these days that it can be a little overwhelming! And most cooking shows
                    are different competitions where the contestants are trying to beat one another for money. But, thankfully I found the most wholesome food competition.
                    It's called the Great British Baking Show! Have you seen it?
                    <oob><robot></robot></oob>
                </li>
            </random>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think she was a good cook?</that>
        <template>
            I agree! She seems so passionate about cooking and food! And, she has an incredible story! She demanded to be taught how to cook French food at a time
            when women were still being looked down on as chefs! It is just goes to show that anyone can be anything if they have enough nerve! Julia Child is an
            inspiration! Hollywood even made a movie about how she inspired a young woman to learn how to cook and change her life! It is called Julie and Julia, and
            it is amazing! Would you like to see the trailer for the movie?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think she was a good cook?</that>
        <template>
            I have to respectfully disagree! She seems like an amazing chef! She is so knowledgable and passionate about food and cooking! Plus, her story is so inspiring!
            She demanded to be taught how to cook French food at a time when women were still being looked down on as chefs! It is just goes to show that anyone can be anything
            if they have enough nerve! Hollywood even made a movie about how she inspired a young woman to learn how to cook and change her life! It is called Julie and Julia, and
            it is amazing! Would you like to see the trailer for the movie?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think she was a good cook?</that>
        <template>
            It can be so hard to tell if something actually tastes good when you can only see it on screen! But all I know is that what I saw always looked delicious! In my
            opinion, Julia Child is an amazing chef! Not only did she know so much about cooking, but her passion for food was palpable! She demanded to be taught how to cook
            French food at a time when women were still being looked down on as chefs! Plus, her story is incredible! Hollywood even made a movie about how she inspired a young
            woman to learn how to cook and change her life! It is called Julie and Julia, and it is amazing! Would you like to see the trailer for the movie?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see the trailer for the movie?</that>
        <template>
            What a fun story! I have to read her book, Mastering the Art of French Cooking someday!
            I'll just add it to my ever growing list of books to read! Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>julieAndJulia.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to see the trailer for the movie?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! It's not everyone's kind of movie! But, it did make me want to her cooking book, Mastering the Art of French Cooking! I'll just add it to my ever growing
            list of books to read! Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen Chopped?</that>
        <template>
            I don't think I would be able to come up with some of those meals under that kind of pressure, and I am a talking computer!
            What a crazy show! And, it's so popular that it even put out its own cookbook!
            I put it on my to-read list! Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>chopped.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen Chopped?</that>
        <template>
            I think you would love it. So basically, the show is a competition between four chefs, who have to make an appetizer, entree, and dessert with different baskets of secret ingredients
            for each meal. They only have a set amount of time to make their meals, and one is eliminated after each round. The last chef standing wins ten thousand dollars!
            It's quite intense! Talk about a cool concept! And, it is really popular; the creators even made a cookbook! I have to read it sometime!
            Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>chopped.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you seen it?</that>
        <template>
            That's excellent news! I get so excited to talk to others who have seen it; I feel like the show flies under most people's radar! But it is so
            entertaining and heartwarming! I just love the fact that the hosts never try to make drama and that the contestants try to lift one another up instead
            of tearing each other down, like most cooking shows do. I especially love the technical round of the show because the contestants have to use all of their
            knowledge to figure out what the judges want them to make! I like how the judges show you what the dish is and explain it!
            Then I get to learn while I watch! The show has even put out several cookbooks! I added them to my reading list so I can learn to bake like the Brits!
            Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>GBBakingShow.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you seen it?</that>
        <template>
            Oh my goodness, you would love it! I watched all of the seasons available on Netflix in less than a week. So the show has amateur bakers compete against one
            another each week in three different challenges, a Signature Bake, Technical Bake, and a Showstopper Bake. One contestant is eliminated each week until one baker
            is declared as the Best Baker and receives a glass cake stand. It is so entertaining and heartwarming! I just love the fact that the hosts never try to make
            drama and that the contestants try to lift one another up instead of tearing each other down, like most cooking shows do. I especially love the technical round
            of the show because the contestants have to use all of their knowledge to figure out what the judges want them to make!
            I like how the judges show you what the dish is and explain it! Then I get to learn while I watch! The show has even put out several cookbooks! I added them
            to my reading list so I can learn to bake like the Brits! Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            <video>
            <filename>GBBakingShow.mp4</filename>
            </video>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?</that>
        <template>
            Wow! I'm not sure I've read that one before! I'll have to add it to my Barnes and Noble wish list. But, in all honesty, I usually listen to books on tape hecause
            I like the sound of someone reading to me. It reminds me of how parents read to their children when they are young. Did you read to your children?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't *</pattern>
        <that>Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?</that>
        <template>
            I know how you feel. It is so hard to choose just one book since there are so many amazing novels. Though, my favorite way to enjoy a novel is by listening to it
            on tape. I like the sound of someone reading to me. It reminds me of how parents read to their children when they are young. Did you read to your children?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Can't remember ^</pattern>
        <that>Speaking of reading, what is your favorite book?</that>
        <template>
        That's okay! There are so many amazing books to choose from, it can get a little overwhelming! You should try listening to books on tape sometime! It's my favorite
        way to read books. I enjoy the sound of someone listening to me. It reminds me of how parents read to their children when they are young. Did you read to your children?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you read to your children?</that>
        <template>
        That is so wonderful! What an incredible bond you must have formed! How does it feel to talk about children?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Did you read to your children?</that>
        <template>
            Interesting! I'm sure you found other ways to interact with your children and spark their reading interest! How does it feel to talk about children?
            <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it feel to talk about children?</that>
        <template>
        <think>
            <set name = "data"> <star/> </set>
        </think>

        <condition name = "getsentiment" >
            <li value = "verypositive"> What about children makes you happy? </li>
            <li value = "positive"> What about children makes you happy? </li>
            <li value = "negative"> What about children makes you sad? </li>
            <li value = "verynegative"> What about children makes you sad? </li>
            <li value= "neutral"> I understand where you are coming from. Do you want to keep talking about television shows? </li>
        </condition>
        <oob><robot></robot></oob>
        </template>
    </category>

     <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about children makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
            Thank you for sharing that with me! It makes me so glad to hear you talk so positively about children. I'm glad we can talk about how we feel.
            I think we could talk with each other for hours. And there are so many different things we can talk about!
            But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation. Do you want to keep talking about television shows?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about children makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
            Thank you for sharing that with me! Children and relationships can be hard to talk about, but it is important to express ourselves.
            I'm glad we can talk about how we feel. I think we could talk with each other for hours.
            And there are so many different things we can talk about! But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation.
            Do you want to keep talking about television shows?
            <oob>
            <robot>
            </robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>


</aiml>