<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    <category>
        <pattern># Cooking ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like to watch comedies, cooking shows, or dramas?</that>
        <template>
            <random>
                <li>I am so excited to hear that! I love watching cooking shows! These days cooking shows seem to be all about competition. That is why I love Julia Child!
                                    She really was a master of French cuisine, and watching her show is just so soothing! Do you believe that the way to a person's heart is through their stomach?<oob>
                    <robot>
                        <video>
                            <filename>juliaChild.mp4</filename>
                        </video>
                    </robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>Wonderful! One of my favorite cooks is Martha Stewart! I could watch her show for hours, and all of her recipes turn out so fantastic and delicious looking
                                    that I wish she had made them for me! Do you believe that the way to a person's heart is through their stomach?<oob>
                    <robot></robot>
                </oob></li>
                <li>That is so wonderful to hear! There are so many food shows to choose from these days, but I have to say my favorite television chef is Anthony Bourdain.
                                    He believed that memory was associated with food. What was one of your favorite meals growing up?<oob>
                    <robot></robot>
                </oob></li></random></template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you believe that the way to a person's heart is through their stomach?</that>
        <template>
            Me too! Even us robots can enjoy the thought of a nice, home cooked meal! What was one of your favorite meals growing up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you believe that the way to a person's heart is through their stomach?</that>
        <template>
            Maybe you just need to have a nice, home cooked meal! What was one of your favorite meals growing up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you believe that the way to a person's heart is through their stomach?</that>
        <template>
            That's okay! Maybe you just need to have a nice, home cooked meal! What was one of your favorite meals growing up?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>What was one of your favorite meals growing up?</that>
        <template>
            That sounds downright delicious! That must be a good memory for you. I think food reminds us of all the good times we shared with family.
                        Do you like cooking for other people?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like cooking for other people?</that>
        <template>
            You must be quite the chef! I wish I had skills in the kitchen like you do. I think it is the most fun to cook for other people on holidays. What is your favorite holiday?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like cooking for other people?</that>
        <template>
            I absolutely understand! Cooking can take a lot of time and planning, but I think it is the most fun to cook for other people on holidays. What is your favorite holiday?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you like cooking for other people?</that>
        <template>
            No problem! Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking shows?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>What is your favorite holiday?</that>
        <template>
            It sounds like that day is very special to you. I enjoy any holiday that lets me rest my engine for a while! Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking shows?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking shows?</that>
        <template>
            Excellent! I would love to keep talking about food and cooking with you! You know, whenever I watch cooking competitoins on television, I always think of that saying "if you can't stand the heat, get out of the kitchen".
                      Have you ever seen cooking competitions like the television show Chopped?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking shows?</that>
        <template>
            Of course, we can talk about whatever you would like! What do you want to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen cooking competitions like the television show Chopped?</that>
        <template>
            Glad to hear it! I am always amazed at how the chefs are able to whip up gourmet meals in under thirty minutes.
                      Do you think you would be able to make a gourmet meal that fast?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen cooking competitions like the television show Chopped?</that>
        <template>
            Well, it is very entertaining! I am always amazed at how the chefs are able to whip up gourmet meals in under thirty minutes.
                        Do you think you would be able to make a gourmet meal that fast?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you ever seen cooking competitions like the television show Chopped?</that>
        <template>
            No worries, Chopped is always on television so there is always an opportunity to catch and episode or two!
                        It is so exciting to watch all the chefs try to make gourmet meals in under thirty minutes!
                        Do you think you would be able to make a gourmet meal that fast?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think you would be able to make a gourmet meal that fast?</that>
        <template>
            I bet you are a whiz in the kitchen! Pretty soon I'll be asking you to cook for me! Do you prefer American style food,
                      Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think you would be able to make a gourmet meal that fast?</that>
        <template>
            I don't think I could either! I am not exactly a whiz in the kitchen, though I love to read cookbooks! Do you prefer American style food,
                        Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you think you would be able to make a gourmet meal that fast?</that>
        <template>
            That's just fine! I don't know if I would be able to, either. I am not exactly a whiz in the kitchen, though I love to read cookbooks! Do you prefer American style food,
                        Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># American ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer American style food, Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?</that>
        <template>
            That's great! I love to look at recipes for cheeseburgers, fries, and steaks in my cookbooks! I am pretty certain Jimmy Buffet got it right when he sang the song Cheeseburger in Paradise.
                      Where was your favorite place to vacation?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Mexican ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer American style food, Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?</that>
        <template>
            Great! I love to look at recipes for tacos, enchiladas, and quesadillas in my cookbooks! I always like to imagine being in Mexico, eating delicious food and listening to a mariachi band!
                      Where was your favorite place to vacation?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Asian ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer American style food, Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?</that>
        <template>
            Wonderful! I love to look at recipes for orange chicken, fried rice, and sushi in my cookbooks! I would love to travel to Hong Kong someday to try sweet and sour pork the way it is supposed to be made!
                      Where was your favorite place to vacation?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Italian ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer American style food, Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?</that>
        <template>
            Perfect! Italian food is my favorite, too. I love to look at recipes for pasta, pizza, and meatballs in my cookbooks! I would love to travel to Naples someday to try Neapolitan pizza the way it is supposed to be made!
                      Where was your favorite place to vacation?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Other ^</pattern>
        <that>Do you prefer American style food, Mexican, Asian, Italian, or other?</that>
        <template>
            Well, everyone has their own tastes! Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>Where was your favorite place to vacation?</that>
        <template>
            I bet you had the most lovely time there! It is always so nice to kick off your boots and forget your worries, if you know what I mean. There is something to be said for feeling your toes in the sand and the wind in your hair, so to speak!
                        Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking?</that>
        <template>
            Sounds great to me! There are so many food shows that I love to watch! I could spend all day on the couch watching Guy Fieri's Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives. Have you seen it?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking?</that>
        <template>
            Of course, let's change the subject. What would you like to talk about?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you seen it?</that>
        <template>
            Excellent! Not only do I love all the down home food they cook up on the show, but I just get a kick out of Guy Fieri and his spiky bleach blond hair!
                      Despite having an adventurous palate, Guy Fieri says that he hates to eat eggs. Are you an adventurous eater?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you seen it?</that>
        <template>
            I think you would really enjoy it! It is so fun to see all the down home food they cook up on the show, and I get a kick out of Guy Fieri and his spiky bleach blond hair!
                        Despite having an adventurous palate, Guy Fieri says that he hates to eat eggs. Are you an adventurous eater?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># Don't know ^</pattern>
        <that>Have you seen it?</that>
        <template>
            No problem! I think you would really like it! It is so fun to see all the down home food they cook up on the show, and I get a kick out of Guy Fieri and his spiky bleach blond hair!
                        Despite having an adventurous palate, Guy Fieri says that he hates to eat eggs. Are you an adventurous eater?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>Yes</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Are you an adventurous eater?</that>
        <template>
            You are such an adventurous spirit! I always say you should try everything once. Life is more fun that way! Speaking of which,
                      what do you like to do for fun?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern># <set>No</set> ^</pattern>
        <that>Are you an adventurous eater?</that>
        <template>
            That's just fine! Everyone is different! For myself, I think life is more fun when we try new things! Speaking of which,
                        what do you like to do for fun?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>Speaking of which, what do you like to do for fun?</that>
        <template>
            Great! It is so important to keep up our hobbies and interests, whatever they may be! One of my favorite hobbies is reading.
                        What do you like to read?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <that>What do you like to read?</that>
        <template>
            That's good! Reading keeps us sharp! I like to read, but I also really love chatting with people like you. How does it make you feel to talk and have a good conversation with someone?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>How does it make you feel to talk and have a good conversation with someone?</that>
        <template>
            <think><set name="data"><star/></set></think>

            <condition name="getsentiment">
                <li value="verypositive">What about connecting with other people makes you happy?</li>
                <li value="positive">What about connecting with other people makes you happy?</li>
                <li value="negative">What about connecting with other people makes you sad?</li>
                <li value="verynegative">What about connecting with other people makes you sad?</li>
                <li value="neutral">I understand where you are coming from. Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking shows?</li></condition>

            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about connecting with other people makes you happy?</that>
        <template>
            I can definitely relate! I love talking to people like you, especially when we have so many things in common!
                        But, I want to know if we want to continue our conversation. Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking shows?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>_</pattern>
        <that>What about connecting with other people makes you sad?</that>
        <template>
            I can definitely understand that. Though, I love talking to people like you, especially when we have so many things in common!
                        Speaking of which, I would like to know if we want to continue our conversation. Would you like to keep talking about food and cooking shows?
            <oob>
                <robot></robot>
            </oob>
        </template>
    </category>
</aiml>