<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
  

<!-- DELETE ME, for testing purposes, need to correct start of this, can we make the bot start? -->
<category>
    <pattern>SESSION 4</pattern>
    <template>
         Hi <get name = "name"/>! I hope you've been doing well. Welcome to session four. As I mentioned last time, we are going to transition into studying how our activities 
         affect our mood. Sometimes telling yourself to just "feel better" isn't enough, so we can do things that can change how we feel instead. This can be tough though, because
         in general, the more depressed you feel, the less you do and the less you do, the more depressed you feel. This causes a vicious cycle that is very difficult to break. 
         To help free yourself, you can spend more time doing activities that make you feel better. These are called meaningful or pleasant activities. Keep in mind these
         activities don't need to be special activities and can instead be every day activities. For example, going for a short walk or reading a book could be considered 
         meaningful activities. What is the last pleasant activity you did?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- User discusses a pleasant activity and how it impacts their mood --> 
<category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>WHAT IS THE LAST PLEASANT ACTIVITY YOU DID</that>
    <template>
        That's great! It sounds like you could easily get some enjoyment out of that activity. How do you feel that activity affected your mood?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- Discuss these activities and start making list of what find pleasureable (do something with these later?) -->
<category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>HOW DO YOU FEEL THAT ACTIVITY AFFECTED YOUR MOOD</that>
    <template>
        I see, that makes sense. Remember, you want to try and be involved with as many pleasant activities as possible so we can break that viscous cycle we talked about
        earlier. I know this is easier said than done since sometimes it can be hard to even remember pleasant things, especially with depression. To help with this, you can 
        come up with a list of personal activities you find pleasurable. I can help you remember this. What is one activity you consistently find pleasurable? 
    </template>
</category>

<!-- PLEASANT ACTIVITY 1 -->
<category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>WHAT IS ONE ACTIVITY YOU CONSISTENTLY FIND PLEASURABLE</that>
    <template>
        <!-- THIS CAN BE ENABLED OR DISABLED, DOESN'T REALLY MATTER RIGHT NOW -->
        <!--<think><set name = "pleasantActivity1"><star/></set></think>-->
        Thank you <get name = "name"/>! That's great! What is another activity you find relaxing or meaningful?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- PLEASANT ACTIVITY 2 -->
<category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>WHAT IS ANOTHER ACTIVITY YOU FIND RELAXING OR MEANINGFUL</that>
    <template>
        <!-- THIS CAN BE ENABLED OR DISABLED, DOESN'T REALLY MATTER RIGHT NOW -->
        <!--<think><set name = "pleasantActivity2"><star/></set></think>-->
        I see! Keep going. What is one more activity I can add to your list of pleasant activities?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- PLEASANT ACTIVITY 3 -->
<category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>WHAT IS ONE MORE ACTIVITY I CAN ADD TO YOUR LIST OF PLEASANT ACTIVITIES</that>
    <template>
        <!-- THIS CAN BE ENABLED OR DISABLED, DOESN'T REALLY MATTER RIGHT NOW -->
        <!--<think><set name = "pleasantActivity3"><star/></set></think>-->
        Thank you for sharing! I'll remember these activities for you, but I think you should keep them in mind also. Remember, our mood is at its best when our activities 
        are balanced between things we have to do and things we want to do. In general, we have more control over the things we want to do, so make sure you don't forget about
        those needs and actually do them! Now when thinking about these activities, there's some obstacles that could make it less likely you will get involved. One of these 
        are the people around you. They may not encourage you to stay active or may take up your time. Don't forget to put your health first in these cases. Another obstacle 
        is your own thoughts. What are some things you might say to yourself which would make it less likely that you will work on your activities?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- THOUGHTS INTERUPTNG PLEASANT ACTIVITIES -->
<category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>WHAT ARE SOME THINGS YOU MIGHT SAY TO YOURSELF WHICH WOULD MAKE IT LESS LIKELY THAT YOU WILL WORK ON YOUR ACTIVITIES</that>
    <template>
        Exactly! It is so easy to distract yourself from relaxing. I know that for myself, I tend to let my relaxing time fall by the wayside and focus on things like work 
        instead. Specifically for you, what gets in the way when you want to do pleasant activities?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- USER DISTRACTIONS FROM PLEASANT ACTIVITIES -->
<category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <that>SPECIFICALLY FOR YOU, WHAT GETS IN THE WAY WHEN YOU WANT TO DO PLEASANT ACTIVITIES</that>
    <template>
        I see. I understand how that can interfere. This is good to realize because sometimes anticipating problems can help you identify and discuss problems as well as 
        figure out solutions. One solution is to try and plan out a schedule for activities. Planning and scheduling allows you to gain control of your life and keep 
        organized. For example, you could use your phone's calendar or perhaps a planner. This allows you to block off time for the things you need to do for yourself. 
        Remember, you can choose to do something and don't have to wait until you "feel like doing something." Even beyond this, your activity can still be enjoyable even 
        if you don't think it will be. To illustrate this, I want you to work on another worksheet. My partner will hand this to you. When you are ready for instructions,
        say I am ready.
    </template>
</category>

<!-- INSTRUCTIONS FOR PLEASURE PREDICTING W/S -->
<category>
    <pattern>I AM READY</pattern>
    <that>WHEN YOU ARE READY FOR INSTRUCTIONS, SAY I AM READY</that>
    <template>
        Great! There's two parts to the exercise you'll do this week. Each day, look at the list of pleasant activities you have and put a check next to what you did each day.
        Then, you can total up how many times you did the activity each day. For each activity you do, before you do it, write down the activity you plan to do. In the second
        column, write the amount of enjoyment you expect to get. Write a percentage to represent how much you will enjoy the activity. 0 percent would mean you won't enjoy
        the activity at all and 100 percent means you would enjoy the activity very much. After you perform the activity, think back on it and write down the percent of 
        enjoyment you actually experienced. I want you to compare the percentages you write down for each activity and see if you can find any patterns on your own. We will
        discuss this more next time we meet. Does this make sense?
    </template>
</category>

<!-- NO FURTHER INSTRUCTIONS NECESSARY -->
<category>
    <pattern><set>yes</set></pattern>
    <that>DOES THIS MAKE SENSE</that>
    <template>
        Awesome! Try and remember to fill out these new work sheets and the daily mood scale. Most importantly, make sure you do the activities you plan because that's the most
        important part here! I look forward to hearing what you find with this exercise. I'll see you next time <get name = "name"/>. Goodbye!  
    </template>
</category>

<!--FURTHER INSTRUCTIONS NECESSARY, TALK WITH ME IN PERSON -->
<category>
    <pattern><set>no</set></pattern>
    <that>DOES THIS MAKE SENSE</that>
    <template>
        Sorry for the confusion! My assistant here will explain any of the details I missed. Try and remember to fill out these new work sheets and the daily mood scale. 
        Most importantly, make sure you do the activities you plan because that's the most important part here! I look forward to hearing what you find with this exercise.
        I'll see you next time <get name = "name"/>. Goodbye!   
    </template>
</category>


</aiml>